故事始于睁眼的瞬间
It began in the blink of an eye.
一架飞机坠落
A plane crash...
一群幸存者
A group of survivors...
-我叫Kate  -我叫Jack
- I'm Kate. - Jack.
一座神秘之岛
An island of mystery.
这地方不同寻常
This place is different.
史诗般的视觉
The scope of it seemed epic.
快来  雀斑女  难道我们不该找点乐子吗
come on, freckles. Don't we deserve somethin' good?
我被彻底征服了
I was blown away by it.
你在哪
Where are you?!
该剧达到以往黄金时档从未达到过的高度
This was something that hadn't been done before in terms of prime time tv.
这里还有其他人
We're not alone.
你一定认为该剧会异常精彩
You could tell it was- it was gonna be cool.
随着大洋航空幸存者们故事的展开
As the story of the oceanic survivors began to unfold...
抬起来
lift!
《迷失》已经成为一种现象
"Lost" Became a phenomenon.
试播的时候就火翻了
whoo! The pilot really blasted off.
激发了全世界观众的想象力
And captured the imagination of audiences around the world.
伙计们  我们在哪
Guys, where are we?
当有数以百万计的观众观看时
When however many million people watched it,
我想我们应该算是成功的吧
I thought, this looks like it might do all right.
很惊艳
It took me by surprise.
我觉得我们在为美国电视改头换面
We were changing the face of American television.
我们到了
We're here.
该剧似乎使用了电视媒体
It seemed to use the medium of television...
我想下面有东西
I think there's something down--aah!
以一种非常具有创造性的方式
In a truly creative way.
Kate  该死  快跑
Kate, damn it, run!
我不知道还有没其他剧本
I don't know of another scripted show
能对文化造成如此强大的冲击力
That has had as much impact on the culture.
救我  爸爸
Help me! Dad!
Walt
Walt!
变数  神秘
Variety, mystery,
未解之谜  国际演员阵容
The big questions, international casting,
难以置信的背景风光
The unbelievably scenic backdrop.
这是幸存者的故事
It's a tale of survival...
亲爱的  等我
是救赎
Of redemption...
我这辈子从没觉得这么正确过
Nothing in my life has ever felt so right.
是信仰
Of faith.
为什么要这样对我
Why did you do this to me?! Why?!
但归根结底
But at its core,
《迷失》讲述的是一群人的故事...
"Lost" Is a story about a group of people...
若不能共融共生  即独自死去
If we can't live together, we're gonna die alone.
相知相爱的人们   我爱你  Penny
Whom we've come to know and love... I love you, Penny.
在过去的六季中
Over the past six seasons.
为什么要你相信这一切这么难
Why do you find it so hard to believe?
为什么你这么容易就相信了
Why do you find it so easy?
从来就没容易过
It's never been easy!
今晚  在《迷死》最终章接近完结之时
Tonight, before the final chapter comes to a close...
你到底想从我这得到什么
What does he want from me? !
我不知道  Jack
I don't know, jack!
让我们来回顾一下该剧...
We're taking a look back...
铭记他们是怎样相爱
To remember how they loved...
他们在那谈得最多的就是爱情
They were all talking about all the chemistry there.
怎么迷失
And lost...
我相当感动  而且还变得有些情绪化
I was pretty moved and I actually got kind of emotional.
怎么争斗
How they fought...
我在这已经有了生活
I had a life here!
Charlie
Charlie!
怎么死去
And died.
该剧对我们的影响力远远超乎预期
It affected everyone a lot more than we expected.
《迷失》联合制片人Damon Lindelof
The cast of "Lost" Join producers Damon Lindelof
和Carlton Cuse
and Carlton Cuse
将与我们分享他们的制片经历
To share their experiences...
正因为打破了这些常规
In breaking all these rules,
才使得《迷失》如此与众不同  -放我出去
That was what made "Lost" Special. Let me out!
这种经历一辈子难求一次
This only happens to somebody once in a lifetime,
-而且还得运气好  -快走
- If they're lucky.  - Go!
它改变了我的生活
It's changed my life.
为那些震撼人心的故事喝彩
And celebrate the story that captured our hearts...
-你必须得离开了  -我不会离开你
- You have to go. - I won't leave you.
挑战我们的思维
Challenged our minds...
-触动我们的生活  -Juliet
- And touched our lives. - Juliet!
拍摄前后  我判若两人
I came in one person and I'm going out another person,
我将终身感激
And I'll be forever grateful.
来世再见了  兄弟
I'll see you in another life, brother.
就像这样  我的视角从这变到这
My vision went from here to here, you know, just like that.
是因为我们注定要做点什么  James
because we're supposed to do something, James.
Sayid
Sayid!
我很高兴  终于快大结局了
I'm so happy with how it's all coming to an end,
感觉很不错  你只需要相信我
And it--it just feels so right. You just have to trust me.
我们开始了
Here we go.
一路走来挺不容易
Quite a journey, y'all.
旅程始于澳大利亚的悉尼
This journey began in Sydney, Australia,
大洋航空815航班的旅客在那乘坐
Where a group of passengers boarded oceanic flight 815
开往洛杉矶的班机
Bound for Los Angeles.
虽是陌生人  但都有共同点
Strangers, but with something in common--
他们都有缺陷  都得独自面对各自的挣扎
They were all flawed and facing their struggles alone.
但他们所共同经历的一切
But what they would experience together
将会永远地改变他们
would change them forever.
故事始于六年前
The story that started six years ago
今晚将会完结
Concludes tonight,
所以我们来回顾一下故事的开头吧
so let us go back to the beginning,
回到《迷失》成为世界奇迹起点的时候
Where the television drama that became a world phenomenon began.
我本打算在试演季去试试镜
I decided to go out on auditions during a pilot season.
Evangeline Lilly 饰 Kate
我当时寻思着  如果试演还能去
I figured, if anything, I'd get, you know,
Jorge Garcia 饰 Hurley
夏威夷度度假  那还挺不错的
a nice little Hawaiian vacation out of doing the pilot.
当我看到剧本的时候
Then when I saw the script,
我的精神顿时就来了
it seemed really ambitious to me.
Terry O'Quinn 饰 Locke
我想《迷失》是我读过的最棒的剧本之一
I thought it was one of the best pieces of material that I'd ever read.
Matthew Fox 饰 Jack
我当时就知道这剧肯定不寻常
I knew that it was something unusual
仅仅看它体现的集体智慧就可见一斑
Just because of the collective intelligence
Naveen Andrews 饰 Sayid
尤其是那些同处一室的人
of the people in the room, probably.
首先很出色的就是  该剧的视野
The first thing that stood out was the--the scope of it.
简直可以说是史诗级的
You know, it seemed epic.
我当时感觉该剧真的能给探索人性
I really got a sense that it would afford
提供很多的机会
a lot of opportunity to explore human nature.
我首次试镜是在2004年1月到3月的时候
That was January of 2004 when I went for my first audition. By March 2004,
当时在夏威夷参加《迷失》的试拍
I was in Hawaii filming the pilot of "Lost."
试拍
救命
Help.
2004年9月22日
On September 22, 2004,
《迷失》在美国首播
"Lost" Premiered in the U.S.,
吸引了1800万观众
And over 18 million viewers were captivated.
救救我  求求你救救我
Help me! Will you please help me?
试拍的经历简直是巨大收获
the pilot was such a great experience.
简直太疯狂了  每天都去那沙滩上
I mean, it was insane just going to that beach every day.
-我宫缩了  -你怀孕几月了
- I'm having contractions. - How many months pregnant are you?
也是初次认识大家
Getting to know everybody for the first time
Emilie de Ravin 饰 Claire
试图理清每个人之间的关系
And just trying to figure out
以及人物角色特点
everyone's relationships and their characters.
喂  你叫什么名字
Hey! What's your name?
Jack
Jack!
对我而言  就像是电影
It looked like a movie to me. If this was gonna be something,
是前所未有的体验
that hadn't been done before,
照网络电视黄金档来说就是这样
in terms of network prime time TV,
是一个极佳的开头
it was a brilliant way to start.
你觉得他们会来吗
You'd think they would've come by now.
我觉得《迷失》是部神作
I thought it was extraordinary.
-谁  -任何人
- Who? Anyone.
我被彻底征服了
I was blown away by it.
-有人看见那东西了吗  -当然
- Did anybody see that? - Yeah.
所有演员都非常激动
All of us as a cast were really excited about it
为我们所拍摄的感到骄傲
And really proud of what we'd done.
觉得是我们完成了独一无二的壮举
We felt like we had accomplished was something special.
好极了
Terrific.
由于该剧的模式极佳
The show's ambitious production style
所以一经问世  立即火爆起来
immediately set it apart.
当Jack  Kate和Charlie去寻找驾驶舱的时候
When Jack, Kate and Charlie went to find the cockpit--
那驾驶舱就是我们来到夏威夷之后
That was the first stuff we ever filmed
拍摄的第一样东西
When we got to Hawaii.
*you all, everybody*
-你从没听过这首歌吗  -听过
- You never heard that song? - I've heard it.
我只是不知道这到底是哪...
I just don't know what the hell it has--
是我们唱的  Drive Shaft乐队
That's us. Drive shaft.
看啊  这戒指
Look, the ring.
就是芬兰的第二次巡回演出的
Second tour of Finland.
我们得抓紧
We gotta keep moving.
那生动的一幕  确实让人印象深刻
And to see that come to life was pretty impressive.
上帝啊
Aah! Oh, my god!
在我们前面拍摄的摄像机抖个不停
There was a camera in front of us bouncing around,
我们也跑得抖来抖去  看上去惊慌失措
And we were bouncing around and looking terrified,
但真实情况是
But we're really just basically
我们当时只是在一个自动式的跑步机上
on a self-propelled treadmill,
而拍摄那一幕  你自己演的时候
And that kind of stuff, you--you do it
你会觉得很可笑
And you feel ridiculous doing it
而看到(处理后)的就真实了不少
and then you see it come to life
你会意识到是多么让人印象深刻
And you realize how impressive it looks.
都是在喷水塔之下拍摄的
That was all shot under water towers,
基本都是些消防软管
Which are basically fire hoses.
体温下降的速度令人难以置信
It's unbelievable how far your temperature drops.
那些充满惊恐的战栗  可不是演出来的
All of that trembling in terror? No acting involved.
我当时被冷死了
I was just freezing.
Jack
Jack!
由于有很多的演员  问题也出现了
A lot of the casting came out of, like,
往往都比较喜欢找和自己相处融洽的演员合作
Finding actors they wanted to work with,
而不看他们是否适合这个角色
Rather than necessarily fill in a role.
-我受够了这个乡下人  -要打一架吗
- I'm sick of this redneck! - You want some more of me, boy?!
我们都是一起的  哥们
Hey! We're all in this together, man.
-都互相尊重点  -闭嘴  死肥猪
- Let's treat each other with a little respect. - Shut up, Lardo.
起初  只是希望我能达标
First it was just, wow, I hope I'm on the level
而不至于被炒  因为他们都是很优秀的演员
And I don't get fired 'cause they're all wonderful actors.
Josh Holloway 饰 Sawyer
当得知  我们基本上得抛开一切
Knowing that we were all gonna basically...
搬到夏威夷去
drop everything and move to Hawaii
而且就真的在那岛上一起生活
And have to live together on an island, literally,
他们想找的是
They wanted to find people
不管在台上台下都能产生良好化学反应
Who seemed to have good chemistry with each other
的演员  -你人不错  我喜欢
On and offscreen. You're okay. I like you.
你人也不错
You're okay, too.
非常感谢扮演角色的多样性
I grew to have such an appreciation for the diversity in- -in these characters
因为能为该剧加入如此这般观点
Because it really added such perspective to the show,
我感觉这剧能把全世界的距离拉近
And I feel like made it a show that the world could relate to.
就是这  宝宝在踢我
there! Right there! That's a kick!
演员阵容空前的国际化
Never before had a seen a cast that was truly international,
Daniel Dae Kim 饰 Jin
在台前台后  这些演员
Both in reality of the actors
不仅是在饰演这些角色
Who were playing the characters and
同时自己也是角色本身
the characters themselves.
来自世界各地的演员
we had people flown in from all over the world.
我来自韩国  Naveen Andrews来自英国
I had just come in from korea, Naveen Andrews from the U.K.
Dominic也是  Emilie来自澳大利亚
And Dominic, of course. Emilie from Australia
Evangeline Lilly来自Canada  真的很不错
And Evangeline Lilly from Canada. It was beautiful.
我觉得我们在为美国电视改头换面
I felt like we were changing the face of american television.
Yunjin Kim 饰 Sun
好吧  如果我是罪犯  那你就是恐怖分子
Fine! I'm the criminal. You're the terrorist.
我们可以各演各的  你要演谁
We can all play a part. Who you wanna be?
我们都近似于十指握紧了祈祷了
We were all just kind of crossing our fingers--
"希望观众能喜欢"
"I hope--I hope they like it."
我当时想  这剧要么红的一塌糊涂
I thought, this is going to either be a huge success,
要么跌入万劫不复的深渊
Or we're gonna go down in flames.
所以试播首映了以后
So it wasn't until the day after that the pilot premiered
我就知道《迷失》肯定有戏了
I knew that I was gonna be doing "Lost" For quite a while.
能行吗
Is it working?
貌似行  只不过没有接收到任何信号
Seems to be, except we're not picking up a signal.
我们只有一个选择可以尝试
There is one thing we could try--
看看在高处能否接收到信号
Seeing if we can get the signal from high ground.
我当时寻思着《迷失》应该有戏
I figured that they would have to give it a shot
因为他们花了这么大一番功夫
Because they seemed to have gone to so much effort
来制作第一集  结果事实证明  千万观众
to produce the first one. However many million people
连续三周都在观看  我当时想
Watched it for three weeks in a row, I thought,
这是不是好的过头了点
Oh, this--this looks like it might do all right for a while.
-快跑  -Sawyer
- Go! Go! - Sawyer!
很明显  《迷失》不是一个寻常的求生故事
It was clear "Lost" Was no ordinary tale of survival,
这只是开始
And this was only the beginning.
记得当时貌似是有个通宵
It was kinda overnight...
伙计们  这只可不止是熊  是北极熊
Guys, this isn't just a bear. It's a polar bear.
我当时刚去健完身  浑身是汗
I was coming from the gym, all sweaty,
有几位女士走过说道
And some girls went by and went,
"哦  你是...这味道...恶心"
"Oh, it's... Ew! Ew!"
我成了"恶心"了吗
And I'm like, "Ew?"
我猜以后刚健完身  肯定不能
Wow, I guess I can't go out in public, like,
再这样出现在公众面前了
Fresh from the gym anymore.
必须得注意形象了
You know, you have to be presentable.
有信号了  求救  求救
Hey! We've got a bar! Mayday! Mayday!
很少有剧能被如此赞扬
It's rare for something to be critically acclaimed
我估计很大部分是来自大众的赞扬
And, uh, I guess, acclaimed by the public.
是遇险信号
it's a distress call.
我想就是在那时候
I think it was at that point that I thought,
事情变得有点...不可预料了
Well, this is turning into something, that, uh, I couldn't really have predicted.
这已经反复播放了16年了
It's been playing over and over for 16 years.
伙计们
Guys...
我们到底在哪
Where are we?
你丈夫也在飞机上吗
So, your husband-- was he on the flight?
没有  我还没结婚
Oh, no, I'm not married.
谁需要男人啊  对吧  那么没用
Who needs men, right? Bloody useless.
《迷失》的核心精髓在于
"Lost" is, at its heart and soul,
角色的研究
a character study.
Damon Lindelof 联合执行制片人之一
作为讲故事的人  我们也很被其中的
We're fascinated, as storytellers,
"人的行为决定了他是怎样一个人"所吸引
by what makes people the way they are.
总的来说  我最喜欢第一季
On the whole, season 1 was my favorite,
那时候我们正在研究人物角色
Where we started to learn about these characters
我们开始关注这些角色
and we started to care about these characters.
因为角色充满了神秘  但又无答案
They were these mysteries that were unsolved
让人很干着急  因为根本没答案
And they were tantalizing because there were no answers.
关于该剧取名为《迷失》
The title "Lost" Was really about
Carlton Cuse  联合执行制片人之一
其实是在隐射这些角色是怎样在生活中迷失的
How these characters were sort of lost in their own lives.
而对我们而言  该剧真正的神秘之处
And for us, the real mystery of the show
不是说"这个岛到底在哪"
Wasn't, you know, "Where is this island?"
而是"这些人到底是谁"
But the mystery of the show was, "Who are these people?"
首先要介绍给各位观众的角色是
And the first character audiences were introduced to
Jack Shephard医生
was Dr. Jack Shephard.
这些角色遭遇了坠机之后
These characters amidst this plane crash
被这个有强烈救生欲望的男人所感染
See this man and sort of activated by his desire to save people.
听我说
Listen to me.
看着我  你会没事的  知道吗
Look at me. You're gonna be okay. Do you understand me?
但你现在坐着绝对不能动
But you have to sit absolutely still.
他当时更像是被选为了领导者
He is elected as the leader a bit,
他当时真的很沉默
And he's really reticent
之所以无法胜任领导者
And doesn't feel equipped to do that
是因为他与他父亲之间还有问题没解决
because of all of his issues with his father.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在说你要把这女孩的囊腔缝好
I'm talking about you stitching up the sac
否则她下半辈子都会瘫痪
So this girl isn't paralyzed for the rest of her life.
Jack活在他父亲Christian的阴影之下
Jack lived in the shadow of his father, Christian...
我知道你不相信我  但我得要他们相信我
I know you don't believe in me, but I need them to.
你觉得确定我才是不相信你的人吗  Jack
Are you sure I'm the one who doesn't believe in you, Jack?
Christian却在悉尼死了
Although Christian died in Sydney...
就是他
that's him.
Jack与他父亲的问题跟他来到了岛上
Jack's issues with his father followed him to the island.
爸爸
Dad?
要知道这种机会可不是每天都有
It's very rare that you would get an opportunity to play
尤其是六年来一直扮演这样一位医生
A character over a 6-year arc that has had such an arc.
-我不是领导者  -但他们都当你是
- I'm not a leader. - And yet, they all treat you like one.
饰演这人的经历
The experience of playing this guy
遭受与他一样的遭遇
and going through what he's had to go through
尽我所能地讲诉他的故事
And trying to tell his story the very best that I can
这种感觉棒极了  这经历让人难忘
Has been great. It's been an amazing experience.
打扰一下
Excuse me!
你有空吗  能帮我个小忙吗
Do you have a second? I could use a little help here.
我是医生  我可以自己缝
Look, I'd do it myself. I'm a doctor.
-但我够不着  -你要我给你缝上吗
- But I just can't reach it. - You want me to sew that up?
-如果你不介意的话  -当然  不介意
- If you wouldn't mind. - Of course I will.
谢谢
Thank you.
Kate
你好啊  美女
hey, girl.
Kate Austen就像是一位邻家女孩
Kate Austen appeared to be the girl next door,
但她在逃避她那不堪的过去
But she was running from a turbulent past.
你真美
You are beautiful.
在杀掉她那有虐待倾向的继父以后...
After killing her abusive stepfather...
Katherine  你干了什么
Katherine... What did you do?
我保护了你  妈妈
I took care of you, ma.
Kate成了一名逃亡者
Kate became a fugitive.
和大多数人一样
Kate's flaws were her--
Kate最大的缺陷  同时也是最大的长处
As with most people, I think- her greatest strengths as well.
就是她的自发性的行为
Her spontaneity was killing her all the time.
她做事从不思考  她是行动派
I mean, she didn't think before she moved. She just acted.
别想跑  Kate
Don't run, kate.
Kate是个杀人犯  很奇怪的是人们
Kate was a murderer, and it's very odd to see people
竟支持杀人犯  就如人们支持Kate一样
get behind a murderer as much as they got behind kate.
-我什么也没干  -你当然干了
- I didn't do anything. - Oh, yeah, you did.
你妈都已经放弃你了  Kate
Your mama gave you up, Kate.
她对别人的关心程度  超乎了人的想象
She really cared about people on a deep, deep level,
到了情不自禁的程度
So much so that she couldn't help herself
以至于有时会鲁莽行事
From acting out- sometimes stupidly.
她在跟踪你们  正如我说的  好奇害死猫
She was following you. Like I said... Curiosity.
不过他们总是被她这种好心肠所感动
But they were always driven by this really big heart
她只是极度迫切地希望看到
that she has that just desperately wanted to see
一切好起来  -我只是想帮忙  Jack
things be right and good. I was just trying to help, Jack.
我想人们对此产生了共鸣
And I think that people sympathize with that.
我想告诉你  我曾做过什么
I wanna tell you what I did.
做过什么不重要  Kate
It doesn't matter, Kate.
我们都应该可以重新开始了
We should all be able to start over.
也正因如此  你也会爱上她这个角色
And I think that's what makes you love her, too.
我要呼吸器的话  又得给你什么
What do you want for the inhalers?
-我要什么是吧  一个吻就行了  -什么
- What do I want? A kiss oughta do it. - What?
一个吻
A kiss.
就是现在和你接吻
From you, right now.
Sawyer
很不错对吧
Nice, huh?!
我更愿意成为Sawyer
for me I would love to be Sawyer because-- shocker!
"因为我简直爱上了Sawyer"
Well-- "Because I'm in love with sawyer..."
"我喜欢把衣服脱了"
"And I like to take off my shirt
"然后看着在镜子面前的自己"
And look at myself in the mirror."
你靠近点给我取取暖如何
How about you come a little closer and warm me up?
你还真会泡妞  Sawyer
You sure know how to make a girl feel special, Sawyer.
Sawyer太有意思了
Sawyer is so fun.
他是个英俊的盗贼  很危险也很聪明
I mean, he's the handsome rogue. He's dangerous. He's clever.
-他擅长嘲讽人  -他取了不少成名外号
- He quips. - There's some good ones.
你还真会拍人马屁  胖墩
You sure know how to butter a man up, stay puft.
我喜欢"胖墩"
I loved "Stay puft."
第一季和Jorge的合作蛮有趣的吧
I thought that was kinda funny in the first season with Jorge,
然后是"清洁工先生"
And then "Mr. Clean."
你只需要带上耳环和一头蓬松的头发
All you need's an earring and a mop.
我想这对Terry的描述恰如其分
I think that perfectly describes Terry.
Lapidus...
喂  Kenny Rogers[著名歌手]
Hey, Kenny Rogers.
Kenny Rogers
Kenny rogers.
你有什么问题吗  "超宽银幕"
What's your problem, Jumbotron?
闭嘴  你这"乡巴佬"
Shut up... Redneck... Man.
有进步
Touche.
叫Hurley外号是非常有趣的一件事
It would be a lot of fun to call Hurley nicknames and, uh--
口头禅就是"婊子养的"
Say "Son of a bitch" All the time?
对  一直挂在嘴边的就是"婊子养的"
And say "Son of a bitch"-- "Son of a bitch" All the time.
来吧  说来听听  -婊子养的
Go ahead. Give it a shot. - Son of a bitch.
婊子养的  婊子养的
Son of a bitch! Son of a bitch!
说的不错  你现在可以把衣服脱了
It's good. Now take your shirt off.
尽管扮演一个说话欠揍的角色很有意思
it's a lot of fun to play a salty character
但也挺有幽默感的
But that has a sense of humor.
不过我有点担心他不能幸存
But I was worried about his survival
因为他太难与人相处了  闭嘴
Because he was so hard. Shut up!
你想知道我是什么样的人是吗  自己读吧
You wanna know what kind of human being I am? Read it.
亲爱的Sawyer先生
"Dear Mr. Sawyer,
你可能不认识我  但我认识你
"You don't know who I am, but I know who you are,
而且我知道你的所作所为
And I know what you done."
躲床下去
get under the bed.
-千万别出声  -开门
- Don't make a sound.  - Open this door!
在他还是个孩子的时候
As a young boy...
James Ford亲眼目睹了父母的被杀与自杀
James Ford witnessed his parents' murder/suicide...
你要干嘛  你想怎样
What are you doing? ! What the hell are you--
一个叫做Sawyer的男人
Brought on when a man called Sawyer
剥夺了他的一切
made off with everything they had.
报仇成了他活着的唯一目的
Revenge became his life's purpose,
从此他以要追杀的这个人的名字自居
And he took on the identity of the man he sought.
这封信不是写给你的  是你自己写的
This letter wasn't written to you. You wrote this letter.
我认为在那特别的一刻  终于有人发现
I think that was a major moment, him being found out--
他深藏多年的秘密
You know, what his kind of dark secret is--
一直以来他自我保护的盔甲终于露出一道缝隙
really put a chink in his armor and...
他仁慈的一面从此流出
allowed his humanity to seep out of that.
我觉得你这辈子从来没拷问过什么人
I think you've never actually tortured anybody in your life.
对咱俩都很不幸的是
Unfortunately for us both...
你错了
You're wrong.
Sayid
我曾是个通讯军官
I was a military communications officer.
我曾参加过海湾战争
I fought in the Gulf War.
你是什么  空军  陆军
What were you-- air force, army?
共和国卫队
The Republican Guard.
Sayid Jarrah的过去黑暗而又痛苦
Sayid Jarrah battled with a dark past.
我觉得你有新能力可用
I guess you have a new skill set you can use.
这马上就能引起你的兴趣
It immediately spikes your interest,
然后你就想  这是个诡计吗
And then you think, you know, is this a gimmick?
为什么他们要这么做  这个人是个好人呢
Why are they doing this? Is this person gonna be a human being,
还是其他什么的
As opposed to some kind of symbol
比如说  不那么吸引人的角色
Or something, uh, shall we say, less attractive?
Noor Abed Jazeem
Noor Abed Jazeem.
我来问你一些问题
I'm going to ask you some questions.
没人叫我"Noor"  Sayid
Nobody calls me "Noor", Sayid.
这个角色不同寻常的一点是他很浪漫
What was unusual was that this character was a romantic.
这不是游戏  Nadia
This isn't a game, Nadia.
而你却一直在玩  Sayid
Yet you keep playing it, Sayid.
内心某处  他还是有很纯洁的地方
Somewhere, there's this part of him that is pure
让他尝试各种赎罪
that will allow him to find some kind of redemption.
这部剧最了不起的一点是
One of the greatest things about this show
编剧们相当聪明
is that the writers were smart enough
总是先给你一个假象  结果截然不同
to show us a stereotype and then flip it on its head.
上周  我们大家还都是陌生人
Last week, most of us were strangers.
不同国家的人们
People of different countries,
不同种族的人们  显然还有不同性别的人
of different races, of, obviously, different genders,
都一直在尝试如何建立一个社会系统
are trying to figure out how to build a society.
但我们现在都到了这里
But we're all here now.
只有上帝才知道我们要在这待多久
And God knows how long we're gonna be here.
这部剧的核心是在问一个问题
At its core, it still is a story that asks the question,
我们能够和谐生存吗
Can we all get along?
但如果我们不能共融共存
But if we can't live together...
那只能孤独死去
We're gonna die alone.
这座岛有很多秘密  但都没有
The island held many mysteries, none more significant
潜伏在丛林中的黑烟更神秘
than the monster that lurked in the jungle.
又来了
there it is again.
但有一人成功幸存  与岛和谐相处
But there was one survivor who embraced the island
并因此产生了新的信仰
and explored it with renewed faith.
Locke
Walt  你想知道一个秘密吗
Walt, do you wanna know a secret?
发现Locke原来是坐轮椅的  太惊讶了
Finding out that Locke was in a wheelchair was huge.
Jorge Garcia扮演Hurley
在最初拍摄的一两集里  我并不知道
Well, I didn't know in the first episode or two that we shot
Terry O'Quinn扮演Locke
Locke实际上是坐在轮椅里的
that Locke, in fact, had been in a wheelchair.
-John  -在坠机之前  John Locke因瘫痪
- John.  - Before the crash, John Locke had suffered
备受折磨  这都是他父亲一手造成的
a paralyzing fall at the hands of his father.
这使他成为一个残疾人并寻求活着的目的
The incident left him a broken man searching for purpose.
飞机上的John Locke
The John Locke that got on the airplane
空有梦想  其它一无所有
just lived in dreams, and he had nothing else.
我觉得他几乎是可有可无的
And I think he was almost an invisible man.
当我看到Locke居然能站起来时
When I saw the scene when Locke stands up...
真是令人动容  这对我来说
and it was very moving and... That, to me, told me something
告诉了我这部剧的发展方向  就好像
about the possibilities for the show. It sort of--
我的视角一下子变大了  就像这样
my vision went from here to here, you know, just like that.
岛上有很多东西提供给我们
There are plenty of things on this island
让我们生存
we can use for sustenance.
那我们到底怎样才能找到这些
And exactly how are we gonna find this sustenance?
我们打猎  就在那一瞬间
We hunt. And all of a sudden,
他领悟到他可以成为这样一个人
the possibility was presented to him that he could be somebody,
他可以决定事情的结果
that he could influence the outcome of events,
而且人们真的会听他的
and that people would actually listen to him.
这简直太诱人了
That was hugely seductive.
我与这个岛对视
I've looked into the eye of this island,
我发现它美极了  我从未听人说过
and what I saw was beautiful. I never heard the voice that said,
"岛是有眼睛的
"This is the eye of the island,
你正与它对视  John
and you're looking into it, John."
但是他将它解释为与岛有特殊的关系
But he interpreted it as having a special relationship
也的确如此
with the island. He made that.
我们被带到这来是有原因的
We were brought here for a purpose, for a reason--
我们所有人
All of us.
是谁带我们来的  John
And who brought us here, John?
这个岛  我一直有种感觉
The island. I always had a sense,
Jack与Locke的分歧将是
you know, that that was gonna be
本剧最主要的矛盾
a fundamental battle in the show was the jack/locke dynamic.
我想这就是为什么
I think that's why
你和我看法不一致  Jack
you and I don't see eye to eye sometimes, Jack,
-因为你是个相信科学的人  -你在想什么
- Because you're a man of science.  -What does that make you?
我是个相信信仰的人  我很容易
I'm a man of faith. It was easy
将Locke的方方面面联系起来
for me to relate to all these aspects of Locke.
我只想待在岛上  住在树林里
I just wanted to stay on the island, live in the woods,
-给大家提提建议  -今天是我生日
- give people good advice.  - It's my birthday today.
至少你和你的孩子  你们生日挨得很近
At least your birthdays will be close together, you and your baby.
-这是好运  -你相信这是好运吗
- And that's good luck.  - You believe in that?
我相信很多事情
I believe in a lot of things.
生日快乐  Claire
Happy birthday, Claire.
谢谢
Thank you.
Charlie与Claire
第一次坠机吧
So... First plane crash?
-怎么猜到的  -我总能嗅到菜鸟的味道
- What gave it away?  - Ah, I can always spot the newbies.
Claire Littleton在坠机前孤身一人
Claire Littleton was alone at the time of the crash,
但很快与Charlie Pace结为好友
but found a friend in Charlie Pace.
他们的关系非常微妙
They had a very interesting relationship.
有很多美好的瞬间  比如花生酱罐子
So many moments were so sweet, like the peanut butter jar.
花生酱
Peanut butter?!
是你点的呀
Just like you ordered.
谢天谢地  是假的花生酱
Thank god it was fake peanut butter
因为我对它过敏很厉害
'cause I'm terribly allergic.
我读这段剧本的时候  我就想  真棒
So I'm reading that. I'm like, oh, great!
我唯一不能吃的东西  他们偏偏给了我
The one thing I can't eat, they got me.
超细腻
Extra smooth.
这是我吃过的最棒的花生酱
It's the best bloody peanut butter I've ever tasted.
这个角色非常好
She's a very sweet,
是那种不会怀揣怨恨的女孩
doesn't-hold-grudges kind of girl.
而她的内心又惊人的坚强
But has this just incredible sort of inner strength,
她不得不在那种荒郊野岭
Having to deal with being pregnant and having a child
挺着大肚子  还要生孩子
in not the comfiest location for that to happen,
很难想象
I would imagine.
Claire  你在这干什么
Claire? What are you doing out here? Mm.
没什么  不用管我  谢了
Nothing. Just leave me alone, please.
有一集我走开了  我当时想
One of the episodes that I walked away from and thought,
哇塞  太妙了
Holy crap, that was so... boop--good,
那集Boone死了
was the episode where Boone dies
小Aaron出生了
and little baby Aaron is born.
准备好了吗  来吧  再来一遍
Ready? Come on. One more.
使劲  使劲  使劲
Push! Push! Push, push, push, push!
生与死
You know, the death and the birth
一条逝去的生命
and the falling away of one thing
换来一个新生命
to give life to a new thing--
这简直太神奇了
It was just executed so dramatically.
那一集真的相当棒
That was a really special episode.
Charlie因此成为了
And Charlie has become
孩子的养父  他们三个
sort of the surrogate father for the child. The three of them
俨然成了《Lost》中出现过的
kinda comprised the closest thing to a nuclear family
最和睦的家庭
that exists on "Lost"
我爱你
I love you.
我们要找什么来着
What are we looking for again?
长的金属或塑料管子
Uh, any long piece of metal or plastic tubing.
只要看上去能做支架的
Anything that looks like, uh, it'll work as a frame.
这部剧第一个真正打动人的情景
The first really profound moment of the show
就是第一季的结尾
was at the end of the first season
-木筏下水起航了  -我觉得这棒极了
- When we had the raft launch.  - Oh, I thought it was pretty great.
能下水  看上去真的像个木筏
You know, pretty seaworthy. I mean, it looked--it was a raft.
这些人找了些看上去能在岛上找到的材料
Those guys made it out of materials that they found
并将其做成了木筏
and could have been on the island.
实际上它比镜头上所看到的更加结实耐用
It was, uh, actually more stable than the camera boat.
组装的真快
It's coming together fast.
这个木筏给这个剧带来了希望
The raft was this real measure of hope for the show--
因为它可能真的能带大家离开这个岛
The idea that they could actually get off the island.
和Jack待在一起  他会照顾你的
那谁来照顾你呢
我觉得这像是达到了一个高潮
I felt like it was a culmination of all the work
大家为此辛苦了一整年
that people had put in for a very difficult year.
我感觉像是在庆祝
And I felt like it was a celebration
这部剧的起源与发展
of where the show started from and where it had come.
起航  保持直行
Lift! And keep it straight!
这个场景让你真正意识到
It's one of those moments where you really understand
制作一部电视剧 需要大家共同努力付出
making of a television series is an incredibly collaborative effort.
推  推  推
Go! Go! Go!
实际上大约有300人共同合作
It's about literally 300 people doing something in unison.
我们写了剧本  然后你们看到成片
You know, we had written the scene, but then you see the film
你们看到Jack Bender[导演]是如何执导的
and you see the way Jack Bender executed the scene,
并感受到所有演员带来的情感冲击
and then you see the emotion that all the actors brought.
我跟你说什么来着
Ah! What'd I tell you, huh?
除此以外  我们与Michael Giacchino[配乐]一起
Then on top of that, we went to the scoring stage
去了录音棚  背景音乐实在太美了
with Michael Giacchino, and the cue was so beautiful
当它结束时  所有人都哭了
That when it was over, everybody was crying,
因为听着音乐响起
Because it was playing
看着木筏起航的画面
and the images of the raft launch were going on,
演奏完之后大家都用弓子
and they all started tapping their bows
敲击乐器  热烈鼓掌
against their instruments and clapping.
那一瞬间感情全部爆发出来
And it was just this profound emotional moment.
看到电视魔术般的将那一场景
To see the magic of television
变得如同史诗一样
make that into a scene that became as epic as it was...
-没错  -简直太神奇了
- Yeah.  - You know, it's almost mythological.
就像荷马创作《奥德赛》一样
It's almost like Homer taking off on his Odyssey.
这是一次英雄般的航行
It's a heroic journey,
-令人敬畏  叹为观止  -没错
- And it was awe-inspiring for me. Literally awesome. - Yeah.
《Lost》的故事需要一个独特的背景
The story of "Lost" required a unique backdrop
使得生存与神秘的故事情节得以展开
where its dramatic tale of survival and mystery could unfold.
夏威夷的欧胡岛成为了最终的选址
The island of Oahu in Hawaii proved to be the ultimate location.
我说"亲爱的  我们要去夏威夷啦"
I said, "Honey, we're going to Hawaii."
Henry Ian Cusick扮演Desmond
然后她问"在哪"  我们就找地图
And she went, "Where is that? " We looked on the map.
我们看着太平洋那片就想  老天啊  就在那吗
And we looked at the pacific and thought, Jeez, that's it?
-周围什么都没有  -夏威夷太棒了
- That's in the middle of nowhere.  - Hawaii's been amazing.
对我们这部剧来说简直太太完美了
It's the perfect, perfect set for our show.
-你们岛在那边  -我真的很喜欢这里
- That's your island.  - I've really enjoyed that.
剧集的大部分场景都在外景拍摄
So much of the show is shot outdoors.
那些山都很美
It has incredible mountains.
气候非常宜人  但是说变就变
The weather can be beautiful, but it can turn.
-雨说来就来说走就走  -雨马上就停  Hugo
- You can have incredible rain. - Storm's about to pass, Hugo.
有时也会有惊涛骇浪
The sea can be treacherous.
有时候会很惨很惨  泥巴会没过你的脚踝
It can be really, really tough. You're in mud up to your ankles,
有时还要在阳光下暴晒很久
or you just spend a ton of time in the sun.
但是剧组都非常非常敬业
And, you know, the crew has just been absolutely amazing.
很多时候我都不知道
I mean, there have been days where I just don't know
那些设备都是怎么搬进搬出的
how the equipment gets in and how the equipment gets out.
非常不容易  但是很值得
It's not easy, but it's worth it.
很美是吧  不论你在岛上待了多久
Beautiful, isn't it? No matter how much time you spend
你永远不会厌倦欣赏这些美景
on the island, you just never get tired of this view.
风景成了剧中的一个角色
This landscape is a character in the show.
Michael Emerson扮演Benjamin Linus
我不知道何时才能再来
I don't know when I'll ever work
像欧胡岛这样美的环境拍戏了
in as magical an environment as I have done here on Oahu.
在长达121小时的剧集中
In 121 hours of the series,
差不多只用到了夏威夷群岛的四处场景
all but 4 scenes were shot in the hawaiian islands.
回过头看  我觉得我们相当出色
Just looking back, I think we did pretty good job
剧情需要拍摄全球各地的场景
Being sort of all over the world
而我们都在夏威夷这就拍了
And shooting everything right here in Hawaii.
您是第一次来突尼斯吗  -不是
- Is this your first time in Tunisia?  - No.
从演员角度看  给我设计的剧情
From the acting point of view, that kind of production design
-有75%的打斗场景  -欢迎来到爱荷华
- is like, to me, 75% of the battle. - Welcome to Iowa.
而事实上他们在这里就能拍摄各地场景
And the fact that they manage to do it here, you know,
在檀香山市中心搭建德国和东欧的场景
in downtown Honolulu, to create Germany, Eastern Europe...
真不可思议  让角色们
The mind boggles. It was very daring
在全世界到处活动真是非常大胆
to allow characters to move between those worlds.
你父亲同意了
在美国电视剧历史上
In the history of American television,
还从来没有一部电视剧
we've never had a television show
在42分钟剧集中只有一半时间有字幕
with half of 42, you know, minutes being subtitled.
这是给你的
这上边列举了一些简单英文单词的读法
每个韩国人都懂一点英语
Every Korean person understands some words of English.
我踩到了该死的海胆
I stepped on a friggin' urchin!
当我听其他人对白的时候  我的任务是
You know, my task, when I was listening, was to pinpoint
尽可能抓住我认为Jin可能明白的词汇
the words that I thought that Jin would understand.
你得赶紧往我脚上撒尿  老兄
You're gonna have to pee on my foot, man.
快尿  尿在上面
Just pee! Pee on it!
-不  不  -快尿
- No! No!  - Pee on--
这样使得他能够理解这些词汇
So that he could hook onto those words
并让他能够与人交流
and give him the appetite to stay in the conversation.
Sun与Jin
我觉得那该归类于
I guess that falls under the category
"小心你想要的"
of "Be careful what you wish for."
你听懂了
You understood me.
你听懂了  对不对  你明白我所说的
You did, didn't you? You just understood what I said.
Sun很神秘
Sun was this mysterious,
非常传统  有时甚至逆来顺受
very traditional, um... even submissive at times,
但她陷入了一场糟糕的婚姻当中
Um, who was sort of trapped in a horrible marriage.
我去哪你都得跟着我
听明白了吗
这个人对他老婆非常刻薄  他只说韩语
This guy was really mean to his wife. He only spoke Korean
并不是一个好交往的人
and just was not a very pleasant guy to be around.
我当时想  我都不知道我是否能做到
And I thought, well, I don't know if I wanna do this.
很高兴我做到了
I'm so glad I did.
扮演这个角色挺有意思的
It's been so much fun playing her...
-怎么了  -我已婚了
- What's wrong?  - What's wrong is I'm married.
一直跟进了解她的所有秘密  非常有趣
And keeping up with her and all of her secrets.
尽管有语言障碍与婚姻冲突
Despite language barriers and marital strife,
但岛上的生活将Sun和Jin拉得更近
life on the island brought Sun and Jin closer,
并给他们带来了对新生活的期望
and offered them hope for a new chapter.
你怀孕了
You're pregnant.
这个孩子是  我的吗
Is the baby... mine?
他的故事发展非常鲜明
His evolution has been pretty marked
也非常有意义
and pretty significant.
我知道我过去
是个什么样的人
我会不惜一切保护你和孩子
我好爱你
无论他们是否幸福
Whether they were happy or unhappy,
我认为这都是个引人注目的爱情故事
it was the love story that I think a lot of people cared about.
有时候真的很滑稽
It was almost comical for a little while.
克服了种种困难  翻越了重重障碍
You know, every possible obstacle you could throw in the way
两个人的心终于回到一起
of two people getting back together.
你不希望他走  是吧
You don't want him to go, do you?
是的
No.
结果却只能隔岛相望
We were gonna be islands apart,
甚至相隔几十年的时空不得相见
And then we were gonna be literally decades apart.
Sun和Jin分开了两季多
Having Sun and Jin be apart for a good two seasons
不仅是在空间上分开  在时间上也是
not only in space but time,
我相信让他们两个重逢
I think it really drew the- the viewers
有个完美的结局
to root for them to get back together
一定会吸引观众的眼球
and have a happy ending.
他们充满信心  一定能找到对方
They had a lot of faith in each other and themselves
但是Sun和Jin并不是唯一一组
To keep searching. But Sun and Jin were not the only survivors
被分开的幸存者
to find themselves separated.
差不多每一季的结尾
At the end of... almost every season,
他们都会设法把大家分开
they would split up the tribe somehow.
你们要想活  就得跟我走
If you wanna live, you need to come with me.
我想第一次重大的分离是
I guess our first big split
一些人想住在洞里
was some people were gonna live in the caves
而另一些人想待在海边
and some people were gonna stay on the beach.
"出岛纪"那集中  一些人乘木筏离开了
And then "Exodus", some people go off on a boat,
另一些人则徒步去找"黑岩号"
and some of us go marching to "the black rock".
第二季开始之后的很长一段时间里
And for a long time, at the beginning of season 2,
感觉好像我们在做两部不同的剧
it was like we were working on two different shows.
而最终  你们也知道
And then eventually, you know,
大家又重逢了  又都在一起了
they rejoined us and then we're back together again.
正像剧中角色那样
Like our characters on the show,
我们从全世界各个地方
we were, uh, we were brought here from all over the world
相聚于这美丽的夏威夷群岛
to this beautiful Hawaii island, and...
我们成了最好的朋友
we became best of friends.
因为我们曾一起乘船出行
Because we were sailing on this ship together
大家和睦相处  对彼此越来越了解
and it was doing well, and--and we were just getting
随着我们的关系逐渐加深
to know each other. As our relationships deepened,
我感觉我们成了一家人
I felt like we became family.
有很多片段
Those closing montages that we had a lot
镜头从大家身边走过
where you just kind of pan across everybody,
看到Sayid扔苹果  我往外倒鞋里的沙子
and Sayid throwing the apple, and I'm shaking sand out of my shoes--
这些都是美好的瞬间  说明"我爱大家"
Those are nice "I love these guys" Kind of moments.
我很可能是对信仰最感兴趣的人
I'm probably most intrigued by faith.
我很喜欢参演那些
I like being on a show
以信仰为主题的剧目
that just talks about faith as a general idea,
关于非常非常相信某事
About just really, really believing in something.
关于将对信仰的热忱付诸于实践
About having heart enough to step forward physically in faith.
为什么你觉得这么难相信
Why do you find it so hard to believe?
-为什么你觉得这么容易  -绝不容易
- Why do you find it so easy?! - It's never been easy!
Loche说"我是相信信仰的人
I mean, Locke said, "I'm a man of faith.
你是相信科学的人"  我总是觉得
You're a man of science. " I always thought
他只是在拼命地追求信仰
he was a man that was desperately seeking faith,
而并不是真正有信仰
not that he had faith.
我认为驱动他的是他需要有信仰
I mean, I think what drove him was the need for it.
如果他能找到有关联的事物
If he could simply find something to connect to,
能够把握住的事物
something to hold on to,
我觉得他一直在追求这些
and I think that's what he was always after.
Locke寻求关联的欲望在他发现
Locke's desire for connection was never more evident
地上那个舱门之前  从未那样强烈过
than when he found a hatch in the ground
他相信它将解开所有迷
And believed it held all the answers.
我已经完成了你要我做的一切
I've done everything you wanted me to do.
那你为什么还要这样  为什么
So why did you do this?! Why?!
当那一束光从舱门照出来的时候
When the lightbulb went on in the hatch,
我觉得那太奇妙了  真的
I mean, I just thought that was brilliant, actually.
一直以来都在铺垫"舱门到底是什么"
You know, you had this whole buildup as to "What is this hatch?"
紧接着一束光照出来  下面有人在走动
And then a lightbulb goes on and somebody walking around down there.
那人是谁
Who is that man?
早在大洋航班坠机之前很多年Jack就遇见过他
It was a man Jack met years before the Oceanic crash.
Jack
Jack.
我叫Desmond
I'm desmond.
祝你好运  兄弟  新生活中再见
Good luck, brother. See you in another life, yeah?
当我最初加入《Lost》剧组时
When I first worked on "Lost",
我不太了解这部剧
I didn't really know anything about the show.
他们给我看了几集
And they gave me some episodes to watch,
我知道了我将扮演舱里那个人
and I realized that I was gonna be the man in the hatch.
放下枪  否则我打爆他脑袋  兄弟
Lower your gun, or I'll blow his damned head off, brother!
但我其实并不知道它将发展到多大程度
But I didn't really realize how big it was gonna be.
是你
You?
这部剧涉及了全世界各地
The show had sort of taken off around the world.
你真的要相信他吗
You're gonna take his word for it?
我们只知道他所说的  Jack
His word is all we have, Jack.
你大可不必相信我的话
You don't have to take my word for it.
看片子吧
Watch the film.
这个舱是有达摩组织建造的
The hatch was one of many research stations
众多研究站之一  上世纪70年代
built by the Dharma Initiative, a group of scientists
致敬![印度合十礼]  达摩计划
一批科学家来到该岛
Who came to the island in the 1970s
来研究这里奇妙的特性
to study its unique properties....
那种独特的电磁波动
unique electromagnetic fluctuations.
Desmond负责每108分钟按动一次按钮
Desmond was charged with pushing a button
用来控制岛上蕴含的
every 108 minutes to keep a massive amount
巨大电磁能量
of electromagnetic energy contained.
您不会经常看到他出场
You don't really see very much of him.
不会了解他的方方面面
You know, you don't know everything about him,
我觉得这让他更具魅力
which always makes him more attractive, I think.
Desmond是个非常有意思的角色
Desmond's a very, uh, a very interesting character
在《迷失》的世界里  他是个常量
within the world of "Lost. " I mean, he's the constant.
另外Desmond还是大洋号空难的原因
Desmond was also the reason for the oceanic crash.
他耽误了向计算机输入代码
He neglected to enter the code in the computer
此时恰逢815航班飞经该岛
just as flight 815 was passing over the island.
因此当Locke执意终止按动按钮之时
So when Locke chose to stop pushing the button,
Desmond意识到问题严重了
Desmond knew the situation was serious.
你要害死我们了
You killed us all.
我喜欢Desmond的是
What I like about Desmond
对于他认为正确的事情
is that he always seems to be doing the best he can
他似乎总会倾尽全力
to do what he thinks is the right thing.
Desmond转动安全开关炸毁了天鹅舱
Desmond turned a fail-safe key to destroy the hatch...
避免了一场全球浩劫
And prevent a global catastrophe.
灾难中他活了下来  -嘿  伙计
He survived the ordeal. - Whoa, dude.
我在这样的丛林里醒过来
I woke up in the jungle like this.
那  天鹅舱把你内裤也炸飞了?
Like, the hatch... Blew off your underwear?
起初那段时间拍摄的确乐趣很多
Yeah, it was a lot of fun working in those early days,
而且Desmond的戏份
And we've come a long way
伴随了我们很长时间  -嘿  在这呢
with the character of desmond. - Hey! Over here!
幸存者随即在丛林中遇到另一个人
The survivors soon met another man in the jungle.
我叫Henry Gale  来自明尼苏达
My name is Henry Gale! I'm from Minnesota!
起初的计划是给Henry Gale三集的戏份
The original deal for Henry Gale was to be three episodes.
Rousseau把他困在了丛林里
Rousseau trapped him in the jungle.
-她认为他是个"其他人"  -什么"其他人"
- She believes he's an other. - An other what?
这个神秘人物
This mysterious man
应该就是"其他人"的一员
was presumed to be one of the others--
小岛的土著
The island's original inhabitants
他们与大洋航班幸存者之间时有冲突
who often clashed with the oceanic survivors.
你不会总是知道如何演绎一个人物
you don't always know exactly how to play a role
当你作为友情嘉宾出演时
when you come in as a guest player...
当然  如果我是他们一伙的...
Of course, if I was one of them--
那些被你们认为敌人的人...
These people that you seem to think are your enemies...
但对于这个角色我的确可以驾驭
But this one I had an instinct for.
很快我就上手了
I knew kind of what to do with it right off the bat.
我会派他们藏到一个隐秘的地方
I'd drawn 'em out to a real secluded place.
当你们的人到那里时  就会落入我们的埋伏
And when your friends got there, a bunch of my people
接着他们就会用你们的人来换我
Would be waiting for 'em, and then they'd use them to trade for me.
所以我不是"其他人"是件好事吧
I guess it's a good thing I'm not one of them, huh?
你们有牛奶吗
You guys got any milk?
可结果证明Henry正是"其他人"的一员
As it turned out, Henry was one of them,
我叫Benjamin Linus
My name is Benjamin Linus, and I've lived on this island
打出生就住在这个岛上
All my life.
Benjamin Linus是"其他人"的首领
Benjamin Linus was the leader of the others,
为了保护小岛他会做任何事
And he would do anything in his power to protect the island.
演绎Benjamin Linus这个角色的妙处
Well, what's fun to play with Benjamin Linus
就在他的飘忽不定
Is the uncertain middle.
不打算交易吗
You're not gonna shake?
我的角色要经常挨揍
I get to be a-a vulnerable character.
Tom  一分钟内要是听不到我的声音
Tom, unless you hear my voice in one minute,
就把他们三个都杀掉
Shoot all three of them.
但有时我必须要极端的冷酷无情
But I also get to be sometimes quite ruthless and cold.
Jack  十分遗憾
I'm so sorry, Jack.
本来我一直认为让人揍自己是Ben
I'd always thought that Ben used taking a beating as a tool
为了获取那些揍他的人情报的一种手段
To gain information about the people that were beating him.
-你失去了谁吗  -你知道我失去了什么
- Did you lose someone? - You know what I lost!
我可以冒昧的说在电视史上
I would venture to say that I am the most beaten character
我是挨揍做多的角色
in the history of television.
所以挨揍也就成了我每天的重头戏
So that's been a big part of every working day.
我特别嫉妒其他的演员
I'm so jealous of the other actors, who, you know,
涂点防晒霜  再把头发弄乱
they put a little sunscreen on and mess up their hair,
然后就可以拍戏了
And they're ready for work.
而我总得早早到片场
I always have to come in early to get
刀口  瘀青  伤痕通通都要弄在身上
these cuts and bruises and wounds and stuff put on me. Uhh!
在Ben脑海里  这是以最小的代价
In Ben's mind, it was a small price to pay
获取情报的手段
to get the informational advantage.
又见面了
Hello again.
如果这是个普通的角色
If he was anything simple at all,
观众恐怕早就厌倦了
the audience would have tired of him before now.
登上这条船  顺着3-2-5的罗盘方位
You're gonna take this boat and follow a compass bearing
要是不出错的话
of 3-2-5, and if you do that exactly,
你们父子就得救了
you and your son will find rescue.
-就这样吗  -绝不食言
- That's it? - Deal's a deal.
编剧们让他在善恶两端
They keep moving him around fractionally
不断地游移
on the scale of good and evil.
就在观众认为这个人物善恶已定的时候
And just when the audience thinks they have him pinned down
编剧就会笔锋一转
then the writers change it up.
你们是谁
Who are you people?
我们是好人  Michael
We're the good guys, Michael.
在这6季播放过程中
Over the course of six seasons,
《迷失》赢得了全球成百上千万忠实粉丝
"Lost" has garnered millions of devoted fans around the world--
其中也包括演员本身
Among them, the actors themselves.
我看到《迷失》大受欢迎
I watch "Lost" to be entertained
看到它走向观众
and to be drawn into these people
走入他们的生活  也看到围绕它的各种争议
and their lives and what they're challenged by.
我儿子喜欢这部剧
I have a son who loves this show,
所以我们一家人一起看
and so we--we watch it together as a family.
我现在是这部剧的狂热观众
I'm a rabid viewer of the show now.
有些演员不看  可我得看
Some actors can't look at the show. I-I have to.
像其他每个人一样  无论他们是否说出来
Like everybody else, whether they'll say it or not,
我喜欢看剧中的自己
I love watching myself.
我绝对是这部剧的粉丝
I'm a fan of the show on a lot of levels,
那种超级粉丝
kind of a clueless fan.
很多电视观众
There are many people at home
要比我理解得透彻
that have it much better figured out than I do.
有的人希望  为了观众着想
There's this expectation that
编剧应该将剧情简单化
you have to sort of dumb a show down to the audience.
我们却有些反其道行之  我们多少认为
We kind of went the other way. We sort of felt like,
应当做一部我们真正欣赏的剧集
let's make a show that we would really appreciate as viewers
因为观众希望更聪慧  希望引入新事物
That tried to be intelligent, that tried to introduce things
那些基于哲学和物理学的深刻话题
That are sort of heavily thematic, based on philosophy or physics.
如果某位编剧特别喜欢Rousseau或Locke的教学
If one of the writers really loved the teachings
那为什么不将剧中人物起为
Of Rousseau or Locke, uh, why not name characters
哲人的名字呢
After those philosophers?
你是Daniel Faraday[物理学家]吗
Are you Daniel Faraday?
Jeremy Bentham[哲学家]
Jeremy Bentham?
Desmond David Hume[历史学家]
Desmond David Hume?
你怎么知道我名字
How'd you know my name?
我们特别喜欢精心隐藏剧中的复活节彩蛋
What we do like to do is hide little easter eggs in the show
就是为了那些想与我们一起
for the people who want to
深入"兔子洞"去看得更细致的观众
go down the rabbit hole with us and
为了了解这些哲人的具体情况
look a little bit deeper. To kind of get at the source of who these people are,
我们查阅了很多资料  读了很多书
we looked at a lot of the things that we had, ourselves, read.
-《沃特希普高地》  -《绿野仙踪》
- "Watership down. " - "The wizard of oz."
-《螺丝在拧紧》  -《镜中缘》
- "Turn of the screw. " - "The looking glass."
现在该看《蝇王》喽
It's "Lord of the flies" time now.
Carlton最喜欢的作家之一是Walker Percy
One of Carlton's favorite authors is Walker Percy.
我们也就让Sawyer看他的书了
Well, we have Sawyer reading walker percy.
你怎么会阅读的
How can you read?
我母亲教我的
My mother taught me.
一旦某本书被用作背景素材  我就想看看
A book that is used as a prop- I kind of want to read it, then,
给事物之间制造联系也很有趣
And it's fun to make connections
也许这有点书呆子气  不过我乐在其中
Between things--maybe a kind of eggheaded fun, but that's me.
因此无论是史蒂芬·金或《圣经》
So whether it was Stephen King, the bible
又或者是《星战》三部曲
or the "Star wars" Trilogy...
他可以随心所欲地冒出来
He turns up whenever he wants,
就像Obi-Wan Kenobi[星战人物]
like Obi-Wan Kenobi.
所有这些迥异的人物
All of these disparate influences
都被我们设法拿来支持这部片子
we kind of tried to bring to bear on the show.
每次台词中将要提到这些人名的时候
Getting to do those references when they would show up...
-就像是...  每次都很震撼
- that was like a... was always a blast.
绝地武士般神奇
Jedi moment.
Hurley可能是《迷失》的粉丝
Hurley would probably be a fan of the show "Lost."
也可能是在《Expose》之后第二喜欢的剧集
It would probably be his second favorite show behind "Expose."
《Expose》是什么鬼东西
What the hell's "Expose"?
史上最牛的电视节目
Only the most awesome hour of television ever.
Hurley
Hurley在某种程度上是个啦啦队长
Hurley is kind of a group cheerleader in a way.
他要让整个队伍撑到明天
He was about getting the whole group
我赌4个木瓜
just to make it to tomorrow. I bet four papayas.
一旦你度过了一关  重点就成了
Once you get past surviving, there comes a point
人们多多少少想找些乐子
where people are gonna wanna be entertained somehow,
我也不知道能有什么乐子  不过我觉得
And I wasn't sure what it'd be, but I felt like Hurley should
Hurley总会弄出些花样  创意节目之类的
do something like put together a talent show or something.
于是就有了高尔夫比赛  那很有效果
Then the golf game showed up, so that works.
伙计们  要是我们困在这里
Dudes, listen, if we're stuck here,
光想着活下去可不够
Then just surviving's not gonna cut it.
我们得想些办法出来
We need some way that we can,
-得找点乐子  此前他们告诉我说
- you know, have fun. I was told early, like,
"你这个角色的故事就是
"Okay, here's what we got for your story.
他中了彩票"  -本期的特选号码是42
It's like, he's a lottery winner. "...With the mega number 42.
很好  可我的奇幻点在哪儿呢
Okay, great, but what's my "Twilight Zone" Thing?
比如我的什么举动每每令他人发出惊呼
Like, where's my twist that makes people go "What?!"
起初我还搞不清楚  直到最后我读了剧本
And I didn't get that till I finally read the script
剧本里说那组数字毁了他的生活
where the numbers that had
最后出现在了舱口上
ruined his life, essentially, end up being on that hatch.
停  那组数字是邪恶的
Stop! The numbers are bad!
接着又在各处钻出来  时钟
And then just popping up everywhere--clocks,
球衫后背  大黄蜂的里程表
Soccer jerseys, the odometer on the camaro.
这就变得有意思了  不管在哪儿
That became kind of a fun thing just-- just everywhere
都能看到它们出现
That stuff like that shows up.
Hurley总是有些霉运伴着
Hurley kind of always had this cloud over him,
每当有倒霉事发生在Hurley身上
And everything bad that happened to Hurley
或者确切说发生在他身边的人身上
Or that--really, that happened to people around Hurley--
他总会埋怨自己  -我真有可能办到
He always blamed himself for. -I could really use a victory.
我们来发动车子  我们来创造自己的运气
Let's get this car started. Let's make our own luck.
Dharma的车对他来说堪称一个重大转折
And the Dharma van is kind of a big turnaround moment for him.
他摆脱掉了生命中的诅咒
He wasn't gonna let the curse control his life anymore.
-Hurley  -好运就在自己手中
- Hurley! - Make your own luck.
根本没有诅咒
There is no curse!
这个死胖子
Son of a bitch.
-知道咱一起的哪个场景我最喜欢吗  -哪个
- You know what my favorite scene was together? - Which one?
就是我们一起坐在货车里那场
The one we're sitting in the van,
-我们还搞到了啤酒  -对  没错儿
- And we've got those beers. - Oh, yes!
你正教我英语
And you're teaching me... English.
某人还迷上了发音
Somebody's hooked on phonics.
你教我学习
You're teaching me the
-那些重要的短语  -对  印象深刻
- important phrases to know. - Yes, that was epic.
这条...  裤子...
Those... Pants...
你穿上...  不显胖
Don't make you look... Fat.
女人只需要听三样东西
Only three things a woman needs to hear.
能放松一下
To kind of be able to relax and, you know,
随便地斜躺着  大家轻松地相互逗着
literally lean back and just have a casual, fun scene
真是让人惬意
什么声音
what's that?
直升机
it's a helopter.
救援到了
Rescue.
货船
退后
stand back!
在岛上经历了90天之后
After 90 days on the island,
幸存者第一次跟外部世界有了联系
the survivors made their first contact with the outside world.
Desmond
Desmond.
一个女人由岛外一只货船
A woman had arrived
来到了这里
from a freighter off the coast of the island.
据说这艘船
The boat was allegedly sent
是由Desmond女友Penny Widmore派来的
by desmond's girlfriend, penny widmore.
但取得联系绝非易事
But making contact would be difficult.
Dharma一个水下舱
An underwater Dharma station was jamming
屏蔽了岛上发射的所有无线电信号
all the radio signals from the island.
-问题就是我们怎么阻止它  -我来
- The question is, how do we get it to stop? - I'll do it.
对我来说  最震撼的一集
For me, the most shocking episode
就是关于Charlie之死那集
was the one that dealt with Charlie's death.
Charlie显然是个非常招人喜欢的角色
Charlie obviously was a very likeable character.
我不会没事的  Claire
I'll be fine, Claire.
别担心我
Don't worry about me.
他们觉得彼此相识已久
They felt like they'd known each other a lot longer.
事情刚刚开始趋于完美
It just evolved into something that was just perfect,
却又陷入无比的悲凉
And now, you know, really sad.
Charlie游向了水下舱
Charlie swam to the underwater station
关掉了屏蔽信号
And turned off the jamming signal...
使他的朋友们有机会呼救
Giving his friends a chance to call for help.
我是Penelope Widmore
This is Penelope Widmore.
-你们如何获取了这一频点  -Desmond
- How did you get this frequency? - Desmond!
你刚才说"Desmond"吗
Did you just say "Desmond"?
-是  你是在船上吗  -什么船  我不在船上
- Yeah. Hey, are you on the boat? - What boat? I'm not on a boat.
对于我们《迷失》编剧们来说
One of the hardest things for us to do
最艰难的事情之一就是杀掉角色
As storytellers on "Lost" Is to kill characters...
很多时候这些角色都是好人
In many ways these characters are friends.
在第三季最后一集我们杀掉Charlie之时
When we killed off Charlie in the season 3 finale,
这令我们考虑了很久
It was something that we deliberated over for a very long time.
不是Penny的船
NOT PENNY'S BOAT
他的死实在太让人感动  我不得不说
How he died was just so moving, and--and I have to say
当我看到Charlie被淹没时留下了眼泪
I was crying my eyes out when I saw Charlie drown.
这真是让人心痛  因为每个人都喜欢他
It really hit home, because everybody loved him.
这对于每个人都产生了很大的影响
It affected everyone a lot more than we expected maybe, too.
也超乎我们预料  当我们走进剪辑室时
when we actually went into the editing room,
Charlie之死的那一刻
the moment when Charlie actually dies
竟是如此令人难过
was this profoundly upsetting thing.
像是失去了自己所爱的人  尽管只是拍戏
It felt like losing a loved one even though it was just pretend.
嘘  Aaron
Shh. Aaron.
-Charlie让我们得救了  -喂
- Charlie just got us rescued. - Hello?
随着屏蔽信号的解除
With the signal cleared,
呼救电话终于有了回应
the call for help was finally answered.
我是大洋815航班的幸存者之一
I'm one of the survivors of oceanic flight 815.
-你能否确定我们的方位  -当然可以
- Can you get a fix on our location? - Hell, yeah, we can!
松糕把我手给烫了
I burnt my hand on my muffins.
从片子的角度来说
I'm interested in the ways that relativity is an issue
我对事物之间相对性的形式很感兴趣
in our show point of view.
这哪儿是什么文学  也就是快餐
It's not even literature. It's popcorn.
什么
Excuse me?
真实只是从某个角度呈现出来
Reality presents itself from one angle,
假如你换个角度换个距离再观察的话
but then if you step to the side or you pull the lens back,
你会意外发现根本不是那么回事
Then suddenly you see it differently.
我倒是觉得自由意志
Here I am, thinking that free will
仍然还存在于...
still actually exists on...
六季的《迷失》告诉我们
Six seasons of "Lost" have taught us
不是每件事物都是起初看起来那样
that not everything is what it initially appears to be.
当别人问起我这部剧时我都会说
I always to say to people when they ask me about the show,
眼见的并不总为事实
what you see is not necessarily what you get.
对前三季来说
For the first three seasons,
角色的闪回揭示了
character flashbacks explored the lives
大洋航班幸存者们
of the oceanic survivors
坠机之前的生活
before they crashed on the island.
但在我们认为的一次闪回中
But everything changed when Jack, in a time of crisis,
当陷入危机的Jack出现时  一切均改变了
was seen in what was perceived to be a flashback.
是我
It's me.
等等  别挂  求你了
Wait. Don't- don't hang up, please.
我只是想见见你
I just need to see you.
但当Kate出现时
But when Kate appeared,
《迷失》向未来跃出了一大步
"Lost" took a giant step to the future
在大结局之前幸存者们
And shattered the expectation
不会离开小岛的希望
that the survivors would not leave the island
也被彻底粉碎
before the end of the series.
我们...  本来不应该离开小岛
We... were not supposed to leave.
不  我们该离开
Yes, we were.
这是剧中第一次利用"闪前"
It was the first in a series of flash-forward storylines
来展现六名幸存者生活的主线
that followed the experiences of six survivors
他们在被营救之后称作"大洋六人组"
who found rescue and became known as the oceanic six.
"我想知道自己夜里是不是变了
"'I wonder if I've been changed in the night.
让我想想  早晨起床我还一样吗"
Let me think. Was I the same when I got up this morning?'"
Jack和Kate生活在了一起
Jack and Kate began a life together
共同来抚养Claire的儿子Aaron
Raising Claire's son Aaron.
作为观众  我们总有这样一种感觉
As an audience, we always got the sense
他们会一起好好相处
that they would be good together.
真高兴你在这里
I'm so glad that you're here.
和Kate一起的那集
That episode with Kate,
他们两人貌似沉浸于爱河之中
we're they're sort of living in a world where they're in love
-然后一起结婚  -当然愿意  我愿意
- and they're gonna get married... - of course I will. Yes.
事情看起来相当圆满
Things seemed to be really beautiful,
但潜伏其下却有件事令Jack纠结
but underneath that is this thing pulling at Jack.
那座遥远的小岛似乎一直在折磨着他
It was like the island was destroying him from afar.
我认为Jack和Kate之所以纠结不堪
I think Jack and Kate struggled as much as they did
完全是因为Kate并不是Jack生活的目的
because ultimately Kate was not Jack's purpose in life,
同时Jack也不是Kate的生活
And jack wasn't kate's purpose.
你不能这样做
You can't do this.
是你的问题  你得想想清楚
You have problems. You need to figure them out.
世间最大的杯具莫过于此:
There's nothing more sad and tragic
你认为两人
than two people that you really feel
本应该好好在一起
would have been great together.
但他们所处的现实情况
But the circumstances that they find themselves in
却无法让他们
doesn't really afford itself to having the opportunity
幸福地长厢厮守
to make a really good, pure connection.
这个让Jack和Kate
And the circumstances that led
最终离开小岛的现实就是
to Jack and Kate's eventual departure from the island
从船上派出的直升机登岛引起的
all began when a chopper arrived from the freighter.
-你是谁  -我是Daniel Faraday
- Who are you? - I'm Daniel Faraday.
我来这儿是救你们的
I'm here to rescue you.
Faraday是位物理学家  他与一个科学小组
Faraday was a physicist who came to the island
和飞行员Frank Lapidus一起来到了岛上
with a science team and their pilot, Frank Lapidus.
但营救并非他们的主要目的
But rescue was not their primary mission.
这是Charles Widmore
This is Charles Widmore-
他的船就停在岛外水域
the man whose boat is parked offshore.
Charles Widmore曾经是"其他人"的首领
Charles Widmore was once the leader of the others
直到被Ben驱逐出岛
before he was banished from the island by Ben.
小子  后会有期
I'll be seeing you, boy.
Widmore计划复仇
Widmore sought vengeance,
因此派出货船来岛
so he sent the freighter to the island,
船上有一干雇佣兵来抓捕Ben
which also carried a team of mercenaries to capture Ben.
走吧  雀斑女  我可在这破地儿待够了
Let's go, freckles. I've seen enough of this rock.
Jack和Sawyer引领一班人向Widmore的船进发
Jack and Sawyer led a group to widmore's freighter...
但是直升机却燃油泄漏
But the chopper began leaking fuel.
要是我们能轻个几百磅
I'd feel a hell of a lot better if we were
我可就感觉舒服多了
a few hundred pounds lighter!
嘿
Hey.
这样Sawyer做了个重大决定
So Sawyer made a fateful decision.
我不知道Kate和Sawyer俩人
I wonder how much of a relationship
究竟该是个什么关系
Kate and Sawyer were supposed to have.
首播那集当我俩拍手枪那个场景时
In that pilot when we did that little gun scene
我把她拉到身前
and I pulled her in close...
我跟你这样的妞儿相处过
I've been with girls like you.
他们都在说  喔  还真来电
They were all talking about, oh, the chemistry there.
不知道是那个场景给了他们灵感
I don't know if that gave them any ideas
还是他们早已计划好了一切
or if they had all that planned already.
在这破岛经历了这一切之后
After all we've been through on this damn island,
我们不该享受下美好生活吗  我总觉得
don't we deserve somethin' good? I always felt, in their flaws,
他们同是天涯沦落人
they were well-matched.
不过共患难让他们
But there is a sort of sweetness about two people
命运纠缠在一起
who know how to stumble together,
而并非是双宿双栖
as opposed to two people who know how to fly together.
Sawyer
Sawyer!
对一个角色来说那有多英勇
how heroic is that for a character?
绝对的英雄
That was extremely heroic.
有人要说  "我们会成功的"
A guy that would say, "You know, we're not gonna make it."
我喜欢  -我跳了
I loved it. - "I'm jumping.
"实际上就如同Josh的真实生活
" Just like Josh in real life, actually.
没错啊  我喜欢那样  我只知给予
It is. I'm--I'm like that. I'm a giver.
Sawyer设法游回了小岛
Sawyer made his way back to the island,
此时Ben已经逃离了雇佣兵
where Ben had escaped the mercenaries...
谢谢你过来  Richard
Thank you for coming, Richard.
并下入一个地下洞窟
and descended into an underground cavern
试图最后保护小岛
in a final attempt to protect the island.
直升机到了Widmore的船
The chopper reached Widmore's freighter,
可船上却被装上了炸药
but it was rigged with explosives.
你要去哪儿  我们得走了
Where you going? We gotta go.
Jin和Michael还在下面
Jin's below with Michael.
不  不  没时间了
No, no, there's no time. There's no time.
-我们必须走了  -我不会离开他的
- We have to go. - I won't leave him!
每次我俩分别的时候都令我难忘
Every time we get separated, it is memorable to me
因为我总会想  会不会这次就是永别了
because I often think, well, maybe this is it.
不  是Jin
No! It's Jin!
我觉得
I think it was
这是我拍摄最艰难的场景之一
one of the hardest scenes I had to shoot.
我的双手在颤抖
My hands were shaking.
不  别掉头
We're not! Turn back!
Sun  Sun  Jin已经死了
Sun! Sun! Jin's gone.
那有可能是他们最后一次相见
That might be the last time they see each other,
所以是非常有意义的  也是Sun相信Jin
so it was significant, and significant for sun
已经死了的标志
in that she believed that jin was dead.
Lapidus  掉头飞回岛上去
Lapidus! Fly us back to the island!
随着货船的爆炸
With the freighter destroyed,
直升机只能原路返回
the chopper made its way back,
同时Ben Linus也转动了神秘的转盘
just as Ben Linus turned a mysterious wheel,
这座岛
causing the island...
消失了
to vanish.
岛去哪儿了
Where the hell's the island?!
不行了  我们快没燃料了
That's it, people! We're out of fuel!
-你回来干什么  -我想洗个澡
- What are you doing here? - I decided to take a dip.
不过我希望人们能记住《迷失》的
But I hope "Lost" is mainly remembered
人物塑造
as a character-driven show...
-你庆祝什么呢  -我没庆祝
- Whatcha celebratin'? - I'm not celebrating.
处理人性问题的方法
That dealt with human issues...
-那个是我们的船吗  -曾经是
- Is that our boat? - It was.
采用的不同视角真的能让你大开眼界
That really opened your mind to different perspectives
甚至你以前想都没想过
that you hadn't thought of before.
我预想过
I have a sneaking suspicion
这部电视剧会是独一无二的
that it might stand alone.
如果10年  15年或者20年过后
I wouldn't be surprised that if you look back on it, you know,
你再看一次的话我也不会惊讶  还会说
10, 15, 20 years from now and say,
-那是过去的电视剧  -John  欢迎回来
- "That was kind of a one-time thing." - " Hello, John. Welcome home."
就所创造的这个世界来说  你可以逃避现实
In terms of creating a world that you can escape in,
我指的是逃避现实的电视剧
you know, I mean, escapist television--
我觉得没有比这个还好的
I don't think it gets any better than this.
有人吗
Anyone?!
时间旅行
当Benjamin Linus转动转轮移动小岛时
When Benjamin Linus turned the wheel to move the island...
他在传送的途中
he was transported halfway around the world
被传到了突尼斯沙漠
to the tunisian desert,
然后他就开始联系已经获救的
and he began making contact with the oceanic six,
-大洋六人组  -你好  Hugo
- who had already found rescue. - Hello, hugo.
不过还在小岛上的Locke  Sawyer  Juliet
But back on the island, Locke, Sawyer, Juliet
还有剩下科学小组成员
and the remainder of the science team
开始了时间旅行
began flashing through time.
在一次时间旅行时
and during one flash...
-Jin  -Sawyer
- Jin? - Sawyer?
他们发现Jin还活着
They found jin very much alive.
-我们得回到兰花站  -你说什么
- We have to go back to the orchid. - Excuse me?
那是一切开始的地方
That's where all this started.
也许也是能终止一切的地方
Maybe it's where it'll all stop.
所以Locke再次转动了转轮
So Locke turned the wheel again,
然后时间旅行就停止了
And the time flashes stopped.
我想已经结束了
I think it's over.
-我觉得是John成功了  -现在怎么办
- I think John did it. - Now what?
现在我们就等他回来
Now we wait for him to come back.
达摩营地 1974
在Locke转动转轮后
After Locke turned the wheel,
Sawyer和Juliet就被留在了1974年
Sawyer and Juliet were left stranded in 1974.
一起留下来的还有Jin和Miles
And with Jin and Miles,
他们都加入了达摩组织
they joined the Dharma Initiative.
用装土豆的袋子做成的连身衣非常搞笑
That potato sack of a jumpsuit was hilarious, man.
你必须每天都得穿着它  你就像是  好吧
You come put that on every day. You're like, wow. All right!
我认为那时候的人都有鬓角
And I think dan had the big sideburns.
我喜欢  在70年代生活也很有意思
I liked it. It was fun to be '70s, you know?
晚上好  boss
Evening, boss.
Sawyer成了保安队的队长
Sawyer became head of security,
Juliet当上了机修工
Juliet was a mechanic...
闻起来真香
Somethin' smells good.
-两人也相爱了  -是送给我的吗
- And the two fell in love. - Is that for me?
不过鉴于Kate和我用了三年时间建立的关系
Whereas Kate and I had three years to earn that relationship,
他们给了我们两种剧本
They gave us two scenes.
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you, too.
但是我看了  我十分确信
But I watched it, and I was convinced.
我几乎马上就支持了Sawyer和Juliet的剧本
I was rooting for Sawyer and Juliet almost immediately.
我是说  Sawyer
I mean, Sawyer--
当暴风雨过去  他和Juliet谈话的那晚
when he was talking to Juliet at night after the big storm,
有点像倾诉关于Kate的心事
you know, sort of pouring his heart out about Kate.
你为什么不现在告诉我呢
Why don't you tell me now?
我无意识的就在想
I involuntarily in my head was thinking,
吻她  吻她
Kiss her! Kiss her!
Locke的旅程
在转动转轮之后  Locke被传送到了
After turning the wheel, Locke was Transported
3年后的2007年
3 years in the future to 2007.
他开始寻找大洋六人组
He began searching for the oceanic six
让他们相信他们必须回到岛上去
to convince them to return to the island.
-我是不会回去的  -答案是  不回去
- I'm not going back. - The answer is "No."
-不  我哪儿都不和你去  -别来找我
- No, I'm not going anywhere with you! - You leave me alone,
你也别再去找他们
And you leave the rest of 'em alone!
Locke失败了  当他失去希望的时候
Locke had failed, and when he lost all hope...
等等  John  停
Wait, please! John, stop.
Benjamin Linus找到了
Benjamin Linus saw a chance
重新当上小岛首领的机会
to reclaim his role as the leader of the island.
你是  你在这干什么
Who--what-- what are you doing here?
那天在那个地方有一种很特殊的干劲
There was a special energy in the room that day.
John  冷静
John, just calm down.
你到底想从我这得到什么
What do you want from me?
-先让我把话说完  -回答我的问题
- Please, let me talk. - Answer the question!
我一直希望Terry能演一场很棒的戏
I always expect Terry to play a great scene,
不过那天他入戏太深了
but he went somewhere further and darker that day.
我不知道我们能从那去哪儿
I don't know where we go from there,
不过我们会弄明白的
But we'll figure something out.
镜头非常犀利
Focus becomes very sharp.
因为这个原因那天也非常紧张和有意思
It was an intense and really fun day for that reason.
我知道我们要去哪儿  在洛杉矶有个女人
I know where we go. There's a woman here in Los Angeles--
叫Eloise Hawking
Eloise Hawking.
Eloise Hawking  你确定
Eloise Hawking? You sure?
对 怎么了  你认识她
Yeah. Why? Do you know her?
没错  John  我认识她
Yes, John. I know her.
我会想念你的  John  真的会想你的
I'll miss you, John. I really will.
我会说那是我面对镜头以来
I would say it was the most intense day's work
工作的最紧张的一天
I ever did in front of the camera.
Locke死去的消息深深的影响了Jack
The news of Locke's death profoundly affected jack
同时也刺激他
and was the catalyst
做出决定返回小岛
in his decision to return to the island.
那里发生了一些事
There was something happening there
甚至与Jack自己都没什么关系
that didn't even have to do with Jack himself.
而是有关他的信念  他和Locke之间的斗争
It had to do with his faith- that whole battle
还有他打算做的事情
with him and Locke and what he's meant to do.
因为他的自由意志他没办法放下那些念头
He cannot let go of the notion that he has free will,
与此同时  这也在不断的摧毁着他
and at the same time, it's destroying him.
他说我必须要回去
He said that I had to come back.
你们所有人都必须要回去
All of you have to go back.
我们也要带他一起回去
We're gonna have to bring him, too.
Jack和Ben两人都想回到岛上去
Jack and Ben both wanted to return to the island,
所以他们找到了一个方法
so they found a way.
Ajira航线  一条航班为3-1-6
Ajira airways flight 3-1-6.
大洋六人组开始了他们回归的旅程
The oceanic six began their journey back.
对于Kate来说
For kate,
是一次让Claire和Aaron团聚的机会
it was a chance to reunite Claire with Aaron.
Shephard先生  你和死者的关系是
Mr. Shephard... Your relation to the deceased?
他  是我的一个朋友
He was, uh, a friend.
为了重现当时航班的飞行条件
To recreate the conditions of the original flight,
John Locke的尸体也被带上了飞机
the body of John Locke was brought on the plane.
在大洋的高空
High over the pacific... Aah!
一道道强光横扫航班
A series of flashes swept through the plane.
那是跑道吗
Is that a runway? !
最后一个引擎也停了  我们要进行迫降
Massive instrument failure! We're puttin' her down!
坚持住
Brace for pact!
Lapidus  Sun还有Ben降落到了现在的2007年
Lapidus, Sun and Ben landed on the island in present day 2007.
-Frank  -他们去哪儿了
- Frank? - Where'd they go?
他们不见了
They're gone.
但是Jack  Kate  Hurley还有Sayid
But Jack, Kate, Hurley and Sayid...
则到了30年前的这座岛  1977年
returned to the island 30 years earlier in 1977...
-Jin  -和Jin还有Sawyer重聚了
- Jin? - And were reunited with Jin and Sawyer.
难以置信
I can't believe it!
你们为什么穿着以前达摩组织的连身衣
So what's up with you guys in the old Dharma jumpsuits?
我们加入了达摩组织  现在是1977年
We're in the Dharma Initiative. It's 1977.
大家一起说"致敬"  "致敬"
Everybody say "Namaste. " Namaste!
Sawyer带他们进入了达摩组织
Sawyer ushered his friends into Dharma society.
别忘了试试这个蘸酱
And don't forget to try the dipping sauces.
他们还做火腿
They really bring out the ham.
Daniel Faraday也成了70年代
Daniel Faraday was also a member
达摩组织的成员
of the 1970s Dharma Initiative...
-你好  James  -他花费了他所有的时间
- Hey, James. - And he spent his days
来找到能阻止大洋815航班
trying to find a way to prevent the crash of oceanic 815
-坠毁的方法  -在天鹅站工地的那些人
- from ever happening. - The Dharma folks at the Swan Worksite--
他们要钻探地下
they're gonna drill into the ground
然后他们会偶然挖到
and accidentally tap into a
-巨大的能量区  -Daniel Faraday说
- massive pocket of energy. - Daniel Faraday says,
如果我们引爆一颗氢弹
if we can detonate a hydrogen bomb,
地下的巨大电磁能量
this massive amount of electromagnetic energy that
那个供研究用的铁舱就会没有用
that hatch is being built to study will be negated.
那个铁舱就不会被造出来
And that hatch will never be built,
你们的飞机就会降落到它的目的地
and your plane will land, just like it's supposed to.
他的想法鼓舞了Jack
His idea inspired Jack.
当Faraday被杀后
And when Faraday was killed...
Jack就去完成了这次任务
Jack carried out the mission.
他们认为这颗炸弹就像是复位按钮
They think that the bomb is like a reset button.
815航班的乘客就回到飞机上
The passengers of flight 815 will be back on the plane,
他们就会从悉尼飞到洛杉矶
they'll be flying to Los Angeles from Sydney,
他们的生活还会继续
and their lives will go on
就好像这次坠机没有发生过
as though there never was a plane crash.
但是这颗氢弹没有爆炸
But the bomb did not detonate...
这里看起来可不像是洛杉矶机场
This don't look like L.A.X.
巨大的电磁能能量
And a surge of electromagnetic energy... uhh!
困住了Juliet
Aah! Had Juliet trapped.
-Juliet  -不
- Juliet! - No! Aah! Ohh!
你以为你能去哪儿  金发妞
Where do you think you're going, blondie?
那是非常棒的一场戏而且也是很好的拍片经验
That was quite a scene and a great experience to film.
-别留下我一个人  -没事的
- Don't you leave me. - It's okay.
别留下我一个人
Don't you leave me!
很艰难的决定  但是是值得的
Tough stuff, but it was- it was rewarding.
我爱你  James  非常非常爱你
I love you, James. I love you so much.
不  不  别放手
No! No, don't let go! Aah!
Juliet
Juliet!
我感觉结束了
I feel like it rounded out
真的以我们的关系
and really honored that relationship we had
或者是角色中我们的爱情为荣
or the love that we shared as characters.
Juliet引爆了氢弹
Juliet survived the bomb...
完成了他们开始的任务
And finished what they'd started.
爆炸啊  快啊
Come on! Come on!
爆炸啊  狗娘养的
Come on, you son of a bitch!
最大的疑问就是
as we move into the final season of the show is,
Juliet引爆那颗氢弹的结果是什么
what is the consequence of Juliet tapping that bomb?
所以在第六季的开始
So at the beginning of the sixth season,
我们是从大洋815航班开始的
we start on oceanic flight 815.
看上去好像氢弹起了作用
And it appears that the bomb has actually worked,
我们的乘客也正飞向洛杉矶
and our passengers are flying to Los Angeles.
-好像我们没事了  -当然没事了
- Looks like we made it. - We sure did.
可是  我们开始认识到
However, we start to realize
这一群人和我们最初看的
that there are subtle differences
电视剧中的那些飞机上的人
between this group of people and what we saw initially
你真的不应该告诉别人
You know, you really shouldn't tell people
-你中了彩票  -谢谢你的提醒
- you won the lottery. - Thanks for the advice, dude,
不过还没有什么坏事发生在我身上
but nothing bad ever happens to me.
我是最幸运的人了
I'm the luckiest guy alive.
在《迷失》里  我们采用了闪回
On "Lost," We've had flashbacks
然后有闪现了未来
and then we had flash-forwards,
现在在最后一季的节目里
and now in the final season of the show
-我引入了平行世界  -有什么不对吗
- we have these things called flash sideways. - Something wrong?
没有  没有  我以前在哪见过你吗
No. No, you just... do I know you from somewhere?
-我也不是很确定  -有很长一段时间
- Well, I'm not sure. - For so long,
这些人的故事都是基于一个想法
these people's stories have basically been governed
这个想法就是这座岛把他们召唤过去的
by this idea that the island is pulling them to it.
我们今年想要讲述的故事
We wanted to tell stories
是出于一个非常特殊的原因
for a very specific reason this year
这座岛其实并没有起到作用
where the island was not in play.
这一次  小岛沉没了
This time around, the island has sunk.
它现在处于大洋的海底
It is now on the bottom of the ocean.
所以在815航班的乘客
And so the passengers of flight 815--
他们正从悉尼飞到洛杉矶的路上
they're flying to Los Angeles from Sydney
就好像从来没发生过坠机
as though there never was a plane crash.
当我们看见飞机
When we actually saw the plane
真的平安降落到洛杉矶机场的时候  我有点
land safely in "L.A.X.," I was just like,
非常非常的激动
it was--it was very emotional.
从飞机上走下来太有意义了
Walking off the plane was so significant.
他们没事了
Wow! They made it.
然后我们的大脑就一直在说
And our brains are telling us,
这是怎么回事  是不是因为
okay, how did this happen? Did it happen because
那个氢弹炸沉了小岛才会这样的
the a-bomb went off and it actually sunk the island?
-又或者是发生了其他什么事情  -有人吗
- Or is there something else going on here? - Hello?!
在那之后不久
then shortly after that,
我们就看到了这些人还在岛上
we see our characters are on the island,
他们引爆了氢弹  可是没起作用
and they've detonated the bomb, and it didn't work.
-不  -他们一下又回到了"现在的小岛"
- No. - They get jumped to what we call "Island present,"
不过他们还是被困在了岛上
but they are still stuck on the island.
你把我们又炸回到了最开始的地方
You blew us right back where we started!
对不起  我以为会起作用的
I'm sorry. I thought it would work.
没起作用
Well, it didn't!
所以观众就要去适应这一切
So the audience is left trying to reconcile,
我们会不会
how is it that we can be watching one story
是在看这些人在岛上
in which our characters are on the island
-深度昏迷时候的一个故事  -是你干的
- and they're in a state of deep misery... - You did this.
我们也看的是这些人
And we're also watching a story in which our characters
在洛杉矶降落下飞机的故事
are landing in Los Angeles, getting off the plane.
然后我们这些观众就向想知道
and so we as an audience are wondering,
-为什么会有这些差别  -非常感谢
- why do these differences exist? - Thank you so much.
在平行世界的时间轴中  Jack是名医生
In the sideways timeline, Jack is a doctor,
同时也是一个少年的父亲
but is also father to a teenage son.
祝你好运  老爸
Good luck, dad.
谢谢  -Kate仍然是一名逃犯
Thanks. - Kate is still a fugitive
不过声称自己是无辜的
but claims she is innocent
不过很快就逃脱了
and quickly makes her escape. Uhh! Ohh!
穿好你的衣服  Jim
Put your damn clothes on, Jim.
Sawyer是一名警察
Sawyer is a cop
每天挣扎于黑暗的过去
but struggles with the same dark past.
Hurley是个彩票赢家
Hurley is a lottery winner,
无论他去哪  好运都跟着他
and good fortune follows him wherever he goes...
人人都爱Hugo
Everybody loves Hugo.
-可是他却情场失意  -我可没时间去相亲
- But he is unlucky in love. - I'm too busy to meet someone.
-没有结婚  -Sun和Jin之间是地下情
- No marry. - Sun and Jin are not married
并没有结婚
yet carry on a secret love affair.
-试着放松  -Claire怀孕了
- Try to relax. - Claire is pregnant and struggling
每天都在犹豫到底要不要这个孩子
with the decision to give up her baby.
Sayid一直苦恼于自己的过去
Sayid is haunted by his troubled past.
他还深深爱着Nadia
He is still in love with Nadia,
但是她却和他哥哥结婚了
but she's married to his brother.
Locke则很高兴和他的女友Helen订婚了
Locke is happily engaged to his girlfriend Helen.
真是爱死你了
You are a very sweet man.
这些故事还涉及到了其他的东西
Mm. These stories are about something else.
他们能再找到其他人吗
You know, can they find each other again?
他们还会影响到其他人的生活吗
Can they impact each other's lives?
如果没有这座岛的介入
Would they ever have met
他们还会相遇吗
if the island hadn't intervened in some way?
Jack shephard  我叫John  John locke.
Jack shephard. I'm John. John locke.
-很高兴认识你  John  -我也是
- It's nice to meet you, John. - Nice to meet you, too.
Locke从没有告诉过Jack他是坐轮椅的
Locke never told Jack that he was in a wheelchair.
恰巧Jack还是一名脊椎医生
Jack just so happens to be a spinal surgeon.
做手术对我来说是没用的
Surgery isn't gonna do anything to help me.
我的病是治不好的
My condition is irreversible.
没有什么病是治不好的
Nothing's irreversible.
这些陌生人开始影响到了其他人的生活
These strangers began to impact each other's lives.
我们是同一架航班上的  Sydney
We were on the same flight-- Sydney.
尽管Kate很明显触犯了法律
Although Kate was clearly on the wrong side of the law...
女士优先
Ladies first.
谢谢
Thanks.
你要保重
You take care.
Sawyer放走了她
Sawyer let her get away.
-开车  我说了  开车  -你在干什么
- Go! I said "Go." -  What are you doing?
她偶遇了Claire
She encountered Claire,
她们两个意外的变成了朋友
and the two formed an unexpected bond.
和一个你一点都不认识不了解的人
It's really cool having these moments with somebody
在一起待一段时间的感觉很棒
that you really know nothing about.
不过你会马上就信任他
But you just immediately trust
-甚至你自己都不知道是为什么  -在平行世界
- and you don't even know why. - In the sideways,
Kate感觉到了她和这个孕妇之间
Kate feels this strange connection with this woman,
有一种奇怪的联系  她想要帮她
This pregnant woman. She wants to help her.
情况很好
Everything is just fine.
你的孩子就是想换个姿势而已
Your boy just likes to move around.
对于我来说
The prospect of that,
对孩子的期望会让我很兴奋
for me, was really exciting.
我喜欢挖掘"如果…将会怎么样"的想法
I loved the idea of exploring the "What if?"
-John Locke丢了工作  -伙计
- John Locke lost his job... - Dude!
有引向了另一段联系
Which led to another connection.
结果是Hurley
Hurley, it turns out, is actually the owner
就是John Locke
of the very company that John
-所工作的公司的老板  -我开了一家中介
- Locke has been working for. - I own a temp agency, too.
而Hurley则反过来给了John Locke
And Hurley, in turn, gets John Locke a job
在这个学校一份代课老师的工作
as a substitute teacher at this school.
有一些老师则是非常熟悉的脸孔
Some of the other teachers there are familiar faces--
最明显的就是Benjamin Linus
Most notably Benjamin Linus.
我觉得我们没见过
I don't believe we've met.
-John Locke  代课老师  -欢迎
- John Locke. Substitute. - Well, welcome.
还是和现实之间
there's little moments of bleed through
-有一些渗透  -也许应该让你来当校长
- between the realities there. - Maybe you should be the principal.
有好几次Ben都以为
There have been times when Ben thinks
以前在什么地方见过他  到底是什么呢
he knows this guy from somewhere. What is it?
你不记得我了  是不是
You don't remember me, do you?
我应该知道你是谁吗
Should I?
这一季会让你来演绎
It kind of gives you a little something new
一些新的东西
to play this season
当扮演他们的时候
In kinda getting to see the other sides of people
就会看到他们另一面
as they played them.
比如说Sun  解开
For sun, the whole buttoning
系上毛衣的扣子
the sweater and unbuttoning it--
在Sun和Jin的平行世界中
She sort of takes that full circle
她有点像在绕圈子
in Sun and Jin's flash sideways--
在Jin的面前脱下毛衣
You know, taking off that sweater right in front of Jin
引诱他
to seduce him.
可是当Sun的父亲发现她的秘密之后
But when Sun's father uncovered her secret,
他就雇人来杀掉Jin
he hired two men to kill Jin.
Jin击败了他们
Jin defeated them.
但是Sun却在交火中中枪了
But Sun was caught in the crossfire.
尽管Sun中枪了
Although sun was shot...
可是一切看起来都还很好  而且
everything seems to have turned out okay, and currently,
她恰巧也是和其他人在同一家医院
she's convalescing in the same hospital
慢慢回复健康
where a number of our other characters happen to be.
-你想怎么样  Jim  -好吧
- What is your deal, Jim? - All right,
听着  我和她一起出去  你别来烦我
look, I go out with her, you gonna leave me alone?
在平行世界中  Sawyer的生活中
In the sideways, Sawyer is a little bit at a loss
在女朋友的事情方面有些不知所措
in his own life in terms of his romantic interests,
Miles则一直试着给他介绍女朋友
his partner, is trying to fix him up
什么人都有  包括Charlotte
with various people, including Charlotte,
也是我们在岛上见过的
who we met on the island.
很高兴见到你  女士
Pleasure to meet you, ma'am.
但是Sawyer却搞砸了
but then Sawyer kind of blows that up.
当他继续着警察生活的时候
As he's going about his life and duties as a cop...
Kate Austen又闯进了他的生活
who runs into him again but Kate Austen.
然后他抓了Kate Austen
And he takes Kate Austen
并把她关进了拘留所
and he locks her up in jail,
他还是和她有一种奇怪的联系
and yet he's still got this strange connection with her,
可是他却不是很明白是怎么回事
and he doesn't really quite understand it.
洛杉矶有那么多车  你偏偏撞到了我的车
Of all the cars in Los Angeles, you smash into mine.
感觉就像有人非要把我们凑到一起
Almost like someone's trying to put us together.
你在和我调情吗
Are you hitting on me?
但是Kate并不是
But Kate isn't
唯一一个吸引Sawyer注意力的人
the only one who captured Sawyer's attention.
一个自动取款机的监控录像
An A.T.M. Surveillance camera
拍到了这个人从犯罪现场逃走的画面
grabbed this jaboney fleeing the scene.
好的  那他叫什么名字
All righty. And the name of that face?
Sayid发现了自己卷入了
Sayid finds himself in a set of circumstances
犯罪活动的事实
where he gets involved in some criminal activity.
还是一个与暴力密切相关的角色
It's still a character that's, uh, near to violence.
就像是相似的命运困住了他
Somehow the same destiny seems to have trapped him.
结果  他逃跑的时候发现自己
As a result, he goes on the run and finds himself
是被Sawyer和Miles追捕的
being pursued now by Sawyer and Miles.
Jarrah女士  我是探员Straume
Mrs. Jarrah, I'm detective Straume.
所以换句话说
So in another way,
我们发下这些角色都是互相有联系的
we find that our characters are all connecting.
在我们看来我们所做的
We do seem to be that the sum total
-那些决定的实质是有联系的  -你被捕了
- of the choices that we make. - You're under arrest.
那些特定的选择能导致很多种结果
Certain choices are invariably full of consequence,
其中的一些结果是非常有害的
and some of those consequences can be quite damaging.
先生  您是医生吗
Sir, you're a doctor?
-是的  -您能跟我来吗
- Yes. - Could you come with me, please?
平行世界中还有一个角色
There's one character in the
-就是Charlie Pace  -他没有呼吸了
- sideways--Charlie Pace... - He's not breathing.
由于他想要藏起来的一小袋
who basically is choking on this bag of heroin
海洛因差点让他窒息  他说他有了一次
That he is trying to conceal. He says that he had
濒死体验  他看见了他所爱的人的画面
a near-death experience, and he saw this image of love.
一个女人  金色头发  非常漂亮
A woman--blonde, rapturously beautiful.
我们知道Charlie爱着Claire
We know that Charlie loved Claire.
在平行世界里  他们从未遇见过
In the sideways, they've never met,
但他却能描述地如此详细
But he's describing her to a tee.
这真是有点诗情画意了  兄弟
Well, that's just... poetry, brother.
Desmond为Charles Widmore工作
Desmond works for Charles Widmore...
-欢迎来洛杉矶  朋友  -谢谢
- Welcome to Los Angeles, my friend. - Thank you.
他被派去监督Charlie
And was assigned to be Charlie's chaperone.
你听过一个叫drive shaft的乐队吗
Have you heard of a band called drive shaft?
不 没听到过
No, can't say I have.
他的生活很空洞  虽然他并没有沮丧
He was leading an empty life. He wasn't depressed,
但是就是少了些什么
But it was just- there was something missing,
他知道生活中少了些什么
And he knew there was something missing,
但是他不知道到底是什么
and he couldn't put his finger on it.
Charlie借机让Desmond看了他看到的东西
Charlie took the opportunity to show Desmond what he saw.
所以Charlie猛转方向盘
So Charlie grabs the wheel.
他让Desmond的车冲出了码头
He takes Desmond's car off this pier,
他们掉进了水里
And they go into the water,
Desmond竭力想把Charlie从车里弄出来
And as Desmond is trying to extricate Charlie from the car,
Charlie把他的手放到了车窗玻璃上
Charlie puts his hand up against the window,
Desmond突然看到了Charlie死时的片段
And Desmond suddenly has this flash of when Charlie died,
写在Charlie手上的是"不是Penny的船"
And written on Charlie's hand is " Not Penny's boat."
当然Demond从没有遇见过Penny
Desmond, of course, has never met Penny,
他没听说过这个名字  但是强烈地
Doesn't know that name, but he has this sort of
感觉到了你无法体会的似曾相识感
profound sense of the most ultimate deja vu
这对他来说意义非凡
you could ever experience. This means something to him.
Desmond
Desmond.
我觉得我好想看到了什么  我看到了光
And I thought, ah, I've seen something. I've seen the light.
不过我觉得远远不止这些
But I think it's even beyond that.
我想他被点通了
I think he's become more enlightened.
谁是Penny
Who's Penny?
Desmond醒悟了
Desmond's awakening
计划好了一系列的行动
Set a series of key events in motion.
两个世界开始移动
These two worlds are starting to move
渐渐靠近
A little bit closer together,
这是因为Desmond Hume有了片刻的觉醒
and the reason is that Desmond Hume had a moment of awareness.
他在岛上的回忆似乎都回来了
He seems to have some complete and total memory of the island.
你能帮我弄到悉尼那趟航班的旅客名单吗
Can you get me the manifest from our flight from Sydney?
大洋815号
Oceanic 815.
我能问一下要来干嘛吗
Do you mind if I ask you what you need it for?
我只是想让他们看点东西
I just need to show them something.
在《迷失》的最后一季
During the final season of "Lost"...
快跑  快跑
Run! Run!
岛上的事情越来越虚幻
The story on the island dove deep into mythology
而且越来越神秘
And explored its great mysteries.
想知道一个秘密吗  Jack
You wanna know a secret, Jack?
我很久很久以前就知道的一个秘密
Something I've known a long, long time?
我们不在岛上  从来没有
We're not on an island. We never were.
我们在地狱里
We're in hell.
我12岁的时候就认识他了
I've known him since I was 12 years old.
他那时候的样子就和现在一样
Richard looked just like he does today.
我开始看出一些端倪
I started to get an inkling
他很特别  比我想象中还特别
That he was a little different than- -than I'd imagined,
我发现他不会变老的时候知道的
Um... I guess when I found out that he didn't age.
这到底是怎么回事
And how the hell do you think that happened?
很久以来  看剧的观众一直想知道
For a long time, people on the show wondered,
Richard Alpert有什么故事
What is the story with this guy Richard Alpert?
这家伙不会变老
The guy doesn't appear to age.
他好像涂了睫毛膏
It looks like he's wearing mascara,
-画了眼线  -这跟他不会变老有关系吗
- uh, eyeliner. - Are these two things related?
-有没有关系  -是啊
- Are they related? - Yeah.
我们确定的是  首先
And we learned definitively, number one,
他没有画眼线
He is not wearing eyeliner.
Richard Alpert的闪回真是让人激动不已
The flashback with Richard Alpert was killer.
我想每个人都喜欢那集  当然我也是其中之一
I think everyone loved that, and I was right in that crowd.
Alpert是19世纪60年代
Alpert was a poor field-worker
加那利群岛上贫困的农民
in the canary islands of the 1860s.
我去请医生
那是一段古装戏  我的意思是
It was a period piece. I mean,
在"迷失"里这段就像一部迷你片
it felt like a mini movie within the context of "Lost."
洋溢着古典的主题和元素
And it had sort of classic themes and elements.
一系列悲惨的事件导致了Alpert的被捕
A series of tragic events led to Alpert's arrest.
他被卖作了奴隶
He was sold as a slave
禁闭在前往新世界的一艘船上
And confined on a ship bound for the new world.
船开往了小岛
The vessel was drawn to the island
在凶猛的暴风雨中船化作了碎片
And shipwrecked during a violent storm.
很多年来  观众一直在想
For many years, the audience has been wondering,
黑岩号怎么会在丛林中间的
How the heck did that ship get in the middle of the jungle?
在这一集里  我们就能知道原因了
And in this episode, we actually finally learn what happens.
备受折磨地过了六天
After six torturous days,
黑衣人把Alpert放了
Alpert was freed by the man in black...
很高兴看到你摆脱枷锁
It's good to see you out of those chains.
但很快他成了黑衣人和Jacob拉锯战中的棋子
But soon became a pawn in his age-old war with Jacob.
我不知道他们会真的
I didn't know that they would really go
在这集里挖得这么深
Into the depths that they did with this--with this episode,
我真的不知道
And I certainly didn't know
这集会和迷联系在一起
That the episode would be tied to the mythology.
我叫Jacob
My name is jacob.
Alpert成了Jacob的顾问  因此得来了永生
Alpert became Jacob's advisor in exchange for eternal life.
我很高兴  不仅因为我参与其中
I was thrilled when I got to not only partake in that
还因为作为捞饭我能知道岛上发生了什么
But also just learn as a fan about what was at play on the island.
把这酒想做你们说的地狱
Think of this wine as what you keep calling hell.
邪恶  魔鬼
Malevolence. Evil.
瓶塞
The cork...
是这个岛  也是唯一一个
Is this island, and it's the only thing
能禁锢住邪恶的东西
Keeping the darkness where it belongs.
初识Jacob和黑衣人的时候
When you're first introduced to Jacob and the man in black,
我们会觉得也许他们是上帝和恶魔
Our assumption is, maybe they're the god and the devil,
他们代表了正与邪  但他们到底是什么呢
Maybe they're good and evil. Who are these guys exactly?
而我们最近才知道  他们是人
And we recently learned, well, they're guys.
要知道  他们是有故事的人
You know, they have a history
就像这个剧里的其他角色一样
Just like any other character on the show.
Jacob和黑衣人是两兄弟
Jacob and the man in black were brothers,
很久以前出生在岛上
Born on the island a very long time ago.
他们由一个妇女抚养长大
They were raised by a woman
那个妇女是小岛的保护者
Who was the protector of the island.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是我们待在岛上的原因
This is the reason we're here.
男孩长成了大人  他们被灌输了一个观念
The boys grew into men and were led to believe
岛外什么都没有
There was nothing beyond the island.
Jacob我要走了
I'm leaving, Jacob.
不  那不可能  根本没有出岛的路
No, that's impossible. There is no way off the island.
最后Jacob被选作了新的守护者
Eventually, Jacob was chosen as the new protector...
现在你和我一样了
Now you and I are the same.
而黑衣人发现他被骗了
And the man in black learned he'd been deceived.
最后  这酿成了莎士比亚式的悲剧
And eventually, this builds to this great sort of shakespearean tragedy
黑衣人杀了自己的母亲
In which... The man in black kills his own mother.
你想离开这里吗  兄弟  那你走吧
You wanna leave this place, brother?! Then go!
Jacob抓住了黑衣人
And Jacob takes the man in black
把他丢进了神秘的洞穴中
And throws him down into this mysterious cavern,
之后黑烟就出现了
And the monster emerges.
这就是
this is the origin of
黑衣人变成黑烟的起源
how the man in black turned into the smoke monster.
成了黑烟之后
Once he is the smoke monster,
它只能变成岛上死去的人的样子
he only can assume the form of dead people on the island.
黑衣人变过Christian Shephard
The man in black appeared as Christian Shephard.
他最多的变成了John Locke的样子
He most notably takes the form of John Locke.
很高兴见到你挣脱那些枷锁
It's good to see you out of those chains.
黑衣人同样也可以
But the man in black can also take the form
变成自己的样子  要离开小岛
Of his own corporal body. To leave the island,
黑衣人必需杀了Jacob
The man in black had to kill Jacob,
但是受规则所限他自己杀不了Jacob
But rules prevented him from doing so himself.
-让我走吧  Jacob  -只要我还活着
- Just let me leave, Jacob. - As long as I'm alive,
你哪也去不了
you're not going anywhere.
我会杀了你的  Jacob
I will kill you, Jacob.
即使你杀了我  也会有人代替我的
Even if you do, somebody else will take my place.
那我把他们也杀了
Well, then I'll kill them, too.
接班人
你不会再偷东西了  是吗
you're not gonna steal anymore, are you?
乖乖的  小Kate
Be good, katie.
我们可以从闪回中看到基本上
We see in flashbacks that basically
在幸存者过去的生活中
Jacob has touched our plane survivors
Jacob都去接触过他们
In their past lives.
选择权在你  Hugo
It's your choice, Hugo.
Jacob的触摸让他们免于死亡
Jacob's touch protected them from being killed
并把他们列入了接班人的行列
And marked them as candidates to be his successor.
所以黑衣人知道这些接班人是谁
So the man in black knows who the replacements are,
他知道大洋815号失事后
And he knows when oceanic 815 crashes
Jacob接班人中的有一些人
That some of Jacob's precious candidates
实际上在那架航班上
Are, in fact, on that plane,
所以他开始寻找到底谁会来接班
so he starts to check 'em out.
我们第一次看到黑衣人
We might just have, uh, first been introduced
可能就是在试播集里
to the man in black in the pilot itself.
他们听到了怪物的叫声
They hear this monster sound-- arrr!
没错  就是这个声音
Yes. That's exactly what it sounded like.
他第一个找到的其中一个就是John Locke
And one of the first people that he checks out is John Locke.
本剧很早的时候
Very early in the series,
黑烟就对Locke很友善
the monster angles in on Locke,
而Locke也说他看到了美妙的东西
and Locke says that he saw this beautiful thing.
也许这就是黑衣人做出决定的时候
Maybe that's the moment when the man in black first decided,
"这就是我要的那个人  我要变成这个人"
"This is my guy. I'm gonna become this guy."
-你活着  -是的
- You're alive? - Yes, I am.
5季以来我一直不知道
I had all of season 5 not knowing
事实上  我就是那个角色
That I was, in fact, that character.
我演得只是John Locke  而现在恐怕已经不是了
I was just being John Locke, who now wasn't as afraid.
什么  John  你不相信我和我的人了吗
What, John? Don't you trust me here with my former people?
我再也不怕你做的任何事了  Ben
I'm not afraid of anything you can do anymore, Ben.
黑衣人出现了
The man in black emerged.
他是一个势在必得的人
This was somebody who was simply gogonna get what he wanted.
黑衣人万事俱备
The man in black had all the pieces in place...
你好  Jacob
Hello, Jacob.
最后他蛊惑Ben杀了自己的仇人
And manipulated Ben to finally kill his nemesis.
现在他正照着他的计划行事
So now he's executed this plan.
到第二步了
It's time for phase two, which is,
为了能让黑衣人离开小岛
In order for the man in black to leave the island,
Jaocb所有的接班人都必须死
all of Jacob's candidates have to be dead.
Ford  你是一个接班人
Ford. You're a candidate.
接什么班
Candidate for what?
成为新的Jacob守护这座岛
Become the new Jacob and protect the island.
我们知道Jack也是接班人
And we learn that Jack is a candidate,
Hurley  死之前的John Locke也是
Hurley was a candidate, John Locke was a candidate
-没错  -他死了之后
- Before he died. Right. - When you die,
就不再是接班人了
you're no longer a candidate...
你需要办个记者招待会和所有一切事情
And you have to have a press conference and everything.
Kwon也是其中之一
Kwon is one of them.
这是指我还是Sun
Does that mean me or Sun?
Jin  这我不太清楚  但是它意味着
Well, Jin, I'm not sure. But what it does mean is that
出岛的唯一一条路就是
the only way we can leave the island is if
名字没有被化掉的接班人一起走
all of the names that haven't been crossed off go together.
黑衣人企图操纵我们的接班人
The man in black is attempting to manipulate our candidates,
而且他努力
And he is trying
营造一个环境可以同时杀了他们
to put them in a situation where he can kill them.
黑衣人招募了Claire和Sayid
The man in black recruited Claire and Sayid.
他想杀了Desmond
He tried to kill Desmond...
他进行了大扫荡
And left a path of destruction in his wake.
黑衣人一系列的精心策划
The man in black's series of calculated moves
让接班人聚到了一起
brought the candidates together.
不  他们丢下我们了
No! They're leaving us!
相信我  你不想登上那个潜艇
No, trust me. You don't wanna be on that sub.
他们上了潜艇
They get on the submarine,
他们觉得自己自由了  可是突然间
And they think that they're free, but all of a sudden,
他们发现背包里装的是炸弹
they discover in this backpack is this bomb.
如果我不把导线拔了
If I don't pull these wires,
Locke会把我们炸上天
Locke's gonna blow us to kingdom come.
不  他不会的
No, he's not!
-Locke杀不了我们的  -什么
- Locke can't kill us. - Uh... What?
他想让我们自相残杀
He's trying to get us to kill each other.
别挡路  医生
Stay out of my way, doc.
倒数加快了  于是Sayid牺牲了自己
The timer accelerated, so Sayid sacrificed himself.
但是爆炸把Sun卡住了
But the explosion left Sun trapped.
Jin  快走
Jin, go!
不  走  我会把她弄出来的
No! Go! I'll get her free!
不  我们能行
No! We can do this!
快走  救Sawyer
Just go! Save Sawyer!
Jin决定留下来和Sun在一起
The fact that Jin decides to stay with Sun--
对Sun和Jin来说是一个
It was just a very heroic, romantic,
很有英雄气概  很浪漫的结局
You know, ending for Sun and Jin.
你快走
You have to go.
我不会离开你的
I won't leave you.
我只是没想到他们让我们分开这么久
I just never expected for them to keep us apart for so long,
当我们再团聚的时候
and only to have us come together
差不多就是死的时候
and sort of be united in our death.
我爱你  Sun
I love you, Sun.
我也爱你
I love you.
他生活中的第一位就是妻子
His one priority in life was his wife.
这样看来  最后他是牺牲了自己
For that, ultimately, he did sacrifice himself,
而这对我来说
And that, to me,
就是最好的结局
is as noble an end as anyone could hope for.
Jin和Sun去哪了
What about Jin and Sun?
"迷失"的最后一集
As the final chapters of "Lost",
两条平行时间线越来越靠近
two parallel storylines are drawing closer together.
-你也在大洋815号上  -是的
- Were you on Oceanic flight 815? - Yeah.
-我也是  -哇  真巧啊
- So was I. - Wow. What a coincidence.
平行世界中  Desmond觉得
In the sideways, Desmond decides it's his mission
出去刺激其他人是他的使命
To go out and basically try to catalyze the other characters
这样他们也能醒悟过来
So they can have their awakenings.
前几天晚上相亲的时候我见到了一个女的
I met a girl on a blind date the other night.
她说我们早就认识对方
She told me that we already knew each other.
那就是我记得了
And that? I'd remember.
她说认识你的时候你相信她吗
Did you believe her when she said she knew you?
那我告诉你  勇敢地去吧
Then I say, go with your gut.
最后  他与Libby重聚了
Eventually, he is reunited with Libby,
他们约会了
And they go on this date,
她有一种奇怪的似曾相识的感觉
And she's having this weird sense of deja vu.
她说不出是什么  但是当他们亲吻的时候
She can't quite put her finger on it. But when they kiss,
Hurley突然记起他们在岛上的情景
Hurley suddenly remembers being on the island.
-老兄  -怎么了
- Dude... - What?
我想我记起来了
I think I'm remembering stuff.
现在他好像和Desmond一样了
And he now seems to be exactly like Desmond.
我们不知道他知道什么了
We don't know exactly what he knows,
但他确实知道很多了
But he certainly knows a lot.
Hurley觉醒之际  Desmond继续
With Hurley on the road to awakening, Desmond moved on
启发着另一个人
to another person in need of enlightenment.
他撞了坐在轮椅里的John  Locke
He literally runs over John Locke in a wheelchair.
这在我看来太直接了
That seems pretty direct to me. And--
"警官  我只是在刺激别人的记忆"
"Officer, I was just catalyzing an awakening."
-谢谢  -别客气
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
Desmond向Sawyer自首了
Desmond turned himself over to Sawyer
与Sayid和Kate一同蹲在了监狱里
And joined Sayid and Kate in jail.
不久之后  Hurley安排了他们的越狱
And shortly afterward, Hurley arranged for their release.
-不好意思来晚了  -别放心上
- Sorry I'm late, dude. - Don't worry about it.
Desmond和Hurley携手并进
Desmond and Hurley are kind of working in tandem
去唤醒其他人
To--to try to help awaken some of these characters.
你跟他  你跟我
Okay, you're with him, and you're with me.
我跟你什么意思
What do you mean, I'm with you?
我们
We...
去个音乐会
Are going to a concert.
我想现在关键的是
I think the point is that we all know everything
我们现在了解了自己需要知道的一切
That we already need to know about ourselves right now.
我们只需要睁大双眼看着
We just need to open our eyes and see it.
Locke先生  你会没事的
You're gonna be okay, Mr. Locke.
Jack发现Locke是他的病人时
When Jack discovered that Locke was his patient...
我想我认识这个人
I think I know this guy.
太巧了没法让人不注意
The coincidence seemed too great to ignore.
出于某种原因
For some reason,
Jack有一种想治好John Locke的强烈欲望
Jack feels this overwhelming desire to fix John Locke,
让他能再次行走
To make him walk again.
做手术的时候  我看了一下你之前脊柱上的伤
While I was operating, I got a look at the initial injury to your spine.
我想我可以把你治好
I think that I could fix you.
深思熟虑之后  Locke接受了Jack的建议
After much contemplation, Locke accepted Jack's offer.
也许发生这一切都是有原因的
Maybe this is happening for a reason.
也许你就该治好我
Maybe you're supposed to fix me.
有一件事奏效的是
One thing that is really coming into play
人物间开始互相寻求帮助
Is this idea of characters asking for help.
我想我准备好摆脱这个轮椅了
I think I'm ready to get out of this chair.
事实上他们能互相帮助
The fact that they are able to help each other
这似乎让他们的生活变得不同
Seems to make all the difference in their lives,
而这也是两个世界的不同之处
And this is a big difference between the two worlds.
在岛上
On the island,
剩下的幸存者为他们先行的朋友默哀
the remaining survivors mourned the loss of their friends.
他们有个女儿  你知道吗
They had a little girl, you know.
Jin还没见过她
Jin hadn't even met her yet.
这都是Locke造成了
Locke did this to them.
我们要杀了他  Jack
We have to kill him, Jack.
我知道
I know.
他们想为发生在朋友身上的事报仇
They want to get revenge for what happened to their friends.
他们想使自己有能力杀了Locke
Um, they wanna be able to kill Locke,
但他们不知道该怎么做
But they have no idea how to do this.
有人让Jack  Kate  Hurley和Sawyer转移了注意力
Jack and Kate and Hurley and Sawyer get sidetracked
那人就是Jacob
By none other than Jacob himself.
我选择了你们因为你们像我
I chose you because you were like me.
你们都孤身一人
You were all alone.
你们都在寻找
You were all looking for something
那里找不到的东西
that you couldn't find out there...
也因为你们需要这个地方像它需要你们一样
Because you needed this place as much as it needed you.
小岛新一代守护者向前迈进的时候到了
The time had come for the island's new protector to step forward.
长期以来  Jack一直在寻找一个原因
For a long time, Jack has been searching for the reason
为什么他被带到这个岛上来
that he was brought to this island and the reason
为什么他回去之后又回来了
that he came back to this island after leaving it.
我来
I'll do it.
他现在确信他到这个岛上来
He now firmly believes that he came to this island
是因为现在保护它变成了他的任务
Because it's his job to now protect it.
这是我应该做的
This is what I'm supposed to do.
那是时候了
Then it's time.
Jack自愿接受了这个任务
Jack takes this mission on willingly,
事实上  对Jack来说
And in fact, for Jack,
这基本上是本剧贯穿始终的
it's a fulfillment of a quest
对于一种追求的满足
That's basically spanned the entire series.
我很高兴它这么结束了
I'm so happy with how it's all coming to an end,
感觉上  感觉上这样做很正确
And it--it just feels so right.
喝了它
Drink this.
我们想让本剧最后一个镜头
We want the last frame of the last show
是关于这些人的
to be about these people
六年前我们把这些人呈现在你们面前
Who we introduced you to six years ago
把你们带上了旅途和他们相伴
and carried you on journeys with and leave you with them
和他们的故事相伴
And leave you with their stories.
这个工作我要做多久
How long am I gonna have to do this job?
尽可能的久
As long as you can.
看到这个剧回到了开始的地方
To watch the show come back to the roots that it started from
并像开始时那样结束了  这就成功了
and end in the same way that it started is a victory.
你不想这本书结束
You don't want the book to come to an end,
但是当你合上书  你会说"天哪  真棒"
but you close the book and you go, "God, that was great."
现在你和我一样了
Now you're like me.
我们希望结束了观众会说
We're hoping for a legacy where people say,
我花了六年时间
"I invested six years of my life
相当关心这个剧
"Really caring deeply about this show,
我感觉这个结局
"And I feel that the way that it ended
展现了  在故事叙述者而言
"Showed an- -an equal amount of respect
关注本剧平等的尊重
In caring for the show on the part of the storytellers."
我们到了
We're here.
我们觉得做了一部自己想做的剧
We felt like we made the show that we wanted to make,
从头到尾都是自己的剧
from start to finish.
我们更想
The larger messages
传递给观众的信息是
that we wanted the audience to take away,
我们感觉已经融入了这个剧  这个结尾
we feel are embedded in the show and in the finale.
对于结局是否能成功而受到威胁的这个想法
The idea that here we are looking down the barrel
其实是一生仅此一次的经历
Of that ending is a once-in-a-lifetime experience.
能成为其中的一部分
Words can't express the gratitude that I feel
感激之情溢于言表
To--to have been able to be a part of that.
看来有人救他出去了
Looks like someone helped him out.
如果心中没有了
It wouldn't be "Lost"
未解之谜  那这就不是"迷失"了
If we still didn't keep a few things close to the chest.
不  Ben  是有人来帮我了
No, Ben, someone helped me out...
因为我要找到Desmond
Because I'm gonna find Desmond.
找到之后  他会帮我做
And when I do, he's gonna help me do
我自己做不到的事
The one thing that I could never do myself.
我要毁了这个岛
I'm gonna destroy the island.
要不是有强大粉丝做后盾
We really don't believe that we ever would have made it this far
我想我们根本没办法走这么远
If it weren't for the incredible, you know,
真是有点腾云驾雾的感觉
Fan base of the show. It's pretty trippy
真的是好极了  作为故事讲述者
And really wonderful. The greatest thing is--
我们远想不到最棒的事是
That we could have ever imagined as storytellers
成为了这个团体的一分子
Was the ability to be a part of that community.
这个剧感觉上已经不是我们做出来的了
This show doesn't feel like it's something that we made.
感觉上有点
It feels like something that kind of,
像是早就存在  而我们只是顺手牵羊而已
Um, you know, existed and we were able to tap into.
我们真的很感谢有这个机会
We're profoundly grateful for having the chance to--
不仅仅创造了那个世界
to not only kind of build that world
并成为其中的一部分
but to be a part of it.